<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

 <title>Pidroh</title>
 <link href="/website/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
 <link href="/website/"/>
 <updated>2023-02-20T20:34:31+09:00</updated>
 <id></id>
 <author>
   <name>Pedro Gabriel Fonteles Furtado</name>
   <email>gabrielpff2@gmail.com</email>
 </author>

 
 <entry>
   <title>February Week 3 - One Last Week of no GRI</title>
   <link href="/2023/02/20/February-w3/"/>
   <updated>2023-02-20T00:00:00+09:00</updated>
   <id>/website/2023/02/20/February-w3</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CARD NOVA / GENERIC RPG WEEKLY REPORT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Second week of the Generic RPG Idle (GRI) break. This coming week will be the last one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Card Nova Hyper is going with me ordering more character art and developing the prototype. I am also setting up things for project Neos, but that is all it is right now, setting up. This setup phase is taking a lot of time. I want to believe it’s worth it but I’m not sure at times. Once Neos starts heating up (if it does heat up since I still have to finish GRI) the new workflow I’m setting up will be useful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is the time table for week 7 of 2023:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;2023 W:07 monster    : 22:08:00
2023 W:07 neos       : 11:47:00
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So yeah, this week wasn’t so productive compared to the others. Still a lot of hours though. But yeah, I’m looking forward to Steam Next Fest and how that might boost Card Nova Hyper AND get me feedback on the prototype I’m working on. Also a bit scared lol.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A wonderful user pointed out performance degradation issues. This means I might have to move GRI to the new technology stack chain before final release. Not sure if this is happening or not. I think I’ll make a decision once the final achievements + story reaches beta.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s goo!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>February Week 2 - Accidents happen</title>
   <link href="/2023/02/15/February-w2/"/>
   <updated>2023-02-15T00:00:00+09:00</updated>
   <id>/website/2023/02/15/February-w2</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CARD NOVA / GENERIC RPG WEEKLY REPORT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ok, first week of a break from Generic RPG Idle. Feels weird.
My computer suddenly had a battery issue. Took me 3 days to fix that. I worked using another computer in the mean time but since I didn’t wanna setup my projects on the other computer, I didn’t work much. I did work though.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Card Nova Hyper I have recently changed the small capsule and the first screenshot of the game. Hopefully this improves the performance of the Steam page. You can see the new screenshot here:
https://store.steampowered.com/app/2197330/CARD_NOVA_HYPER/
And the new capsule by clicking here:
https://store.steampowered.com/search/?term=card+nova+hyper&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My card game prototype is also going great. I’m not feature complete but I’m close. Steam Next Fest registration is up until March 16 so I’ll see if I can make that deadline for a little spin off title!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is the time table for week 6 of 2023:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;2023 W:06 manager    :  2:36:00
2023 W:06 monster    : 33:57:00
2023 W:06 hrpg       :  0:14:00
2023 W:06 burocracy  :  0:32:00
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SO yeah, computer broken, less hours worked on the game. But things are going.
This week I’ll also rest on GRI. And then the next one I’ll rest too. After that development should resume.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s goo!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>February Week 1 - Last day to get Generic RPG Idle on a discount!</title>
   <link href="/2023/02/06/February-w1/"/>
   <updated>2023-02-06T00:00:00+09:00</updated>
   <id>/website/2023/02/06/February-w1</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CARD NOVA / GENERIC RPG WEEKLY REPORT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last days to get Generic RPG Idle!!
This week I ended up doing 10 hours of Generic RPG Idle related tasks! Considering I wanted to take a 3/4 week break from it, I failed lol.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is the time table for week 5 of 2023:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;2023 W:05 monster    : 30:48:00
2023 W:05 hrpg       : 10:43:00
2023 W:05 manager    :  3:14:00
2023 W:05 neos       :  1:27:00
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;8 hours of streaming this week! And on only 3 days. It really helps concentration!
Since I don’t wanna build just the card game while I’m taking a break from GRI, I’m thinking about starting on the next prototype.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This new update set a new record of sales for GRI, so that was awesome!! Thanks everyone for your support!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>January Week 4 - New GRI version available now!</title>
   <link href="/2023/01/30/January-w4/"/>
   <updated>2023-01-30T00:00:00+09:00</updated>
   <id>/website/2023/01/30/January-w4</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CARD NOVA / GENERIC RPG WEEKLY REPORT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The new update is up for Generic RPG Idle!!
The sale starts at 10am Pacific Time!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I spent a lot of time this week doing release stuff for GRI. I also added some requested features and fixed some small issues.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is the time table for week 4 of 2023:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;2023 W:04 monster    : 18:57:00
2023 W:04 hrpg       : 31:09:00
2023 W:04 manager    :  0:35:00
2023 W:04 burocracy  :  0:34:00
2023 W:04 marketing  :  0:54:00
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I did almost 5 hours of streaming this week. Not bad. Working on release stuff on GRI did stop me from streaming more. We’ll see how that goes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since I have decided to work on GRI 10 hours per week for a while, I think I’ll take a two week break from it. I mean, there is some stuff I still have to do related to the release but I won’t do more than that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Forgot to update the trailer in the Steam page, will do that now!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hope people like the update!!
Peace!&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>January Week 3 - Mew GRI Version Next Week!</title>
   <link href="/2023/01/23/January-w3/"/>
   <updated>2023-01-23T00:00:00+09:00</updated>
   <id>/website/2023/01/23/January-w3</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CARD NOVA / GENERIC RPG WEEKLY REPORT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Beta is still going for GRI, instructions are here:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://store.steampowered.com/news/app/1858120/view/5281067109624265833&quot;&gt;Beta instructions&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have submitted Generic RPG Idle for BitSummit!!! Really hope I can participate.
I wanted to send Card Nova Hyper too, but it requires a playable build. Next year, I guess.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is the time table for week 3:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;2023 W:03 monster    : 24:07:00
2023 W:03 manager    :  2:33:00
2023 W:03 hrpg       : 10:45:00
2023 W:03 burocracy  :  2:10:00
2023 W:03 marketing  :  0:18:00
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I streamed for around four hours. I don’t really wanna focus too much on it, but I do want to increase my hours. Maybe I can focus on increasing the hours in February.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>January Week 2 - GRI Beta is up!!</title>
   <link href="/2023/01/16/January-w2/"/>
   <updated>2023-01-16T00:00:00+09:00</updated>
   <id>/website/2023/01/16/January-w2</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CARD NOVA / GENERIC RPG WEEKLY REPORT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have FINALLY finished the “Sound of Art” update for Generic RPG Idle, which adds sound to the game. This one required collaboration with multiple professionals to make happen. Good thing is my sound code is fairly stable now. That means I’ll have an easier time when doing sound for CARD NOVA!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=pj6t1ohP9g4&quot;&gt;===&amp;gt; NEW TRAILER &amp;lt;===&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have a beta available for the new version of GRI, instructions are here:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://store.steampowered.com/news/app/1858120/view/5281067109624265833&quot;&gt;Beta instructions&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Card Nova’s prototype is going well. I am considering sharing some WIP artwork, not sure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is the time table for week 2:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;2023 W:02 monster    	 : 34:45:00
2023 W:02 manager    	 :  1:24:00
2023 W:02 hrpg       	 : 13:23:00
2023 W:02 monster_stream :  1:40:00
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I streamed! And I also measured it. It increases my concentration, so I am trying to stream development. I don’t really have a schedule right now, just do it periodically. I’ll try to expand the number of hours I stream weekly, if it feels sustainable I’ll consider deciding on a schedule.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>January Week 1 and happy new year!</title>
   <link href="/2023/01/10/January-w1/"/>
   <updated>2023-01-10T00:00:00+09:00</updated>
   <id>/website/2023/01/10/January-w1</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CARD NOVA / GENERIC RPG WEEKLY REPORT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hey, everyone! 
This week I finished up creating/polishing the music / sfx system for GRI. Then I fixed some weird bugs I found. Next I wanna do some QOL stuff that one user asked for. 
GRI for Switch is still not guaranteed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For Card Nova, I am making a prototype and seeing how localization would work. Yeah, I wanna get localization working very early so that I can localize the game more freely. The very early prototype I have for the card game allows players to upgrade their cards and fight duels. It’s not exactly the most playable prototype, but it’s there. I’m currently seeing how to render Chinese characters and I think I found a nice font (if not too small).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wishlist behavior for Card Nova has been very different from GRI. The game exploded. And then faded. Steam page reveal Wishlists for Card Nova were much higher than GRI. Even before press coverage. But after a couple of weeks, Wishlist count is lower than GRI. I’m not sure on what to think of this. 
My current theory is that my tag setup gives you a lot of Wishlists when your game is booming (“newly added page”, new trailer, etc) by showing it in popular game pages. But not so much when things are going slow. While Generic RPG Idle only shows up in other niche games, so even a slow week is a healthy week, kinda? I might retag Card Nova Hyper by rexamining what I should compete with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No time table for this week. End of the year always bugs my data and I don’t really wanna fix it. It was a good week though.
Hope 2023 is going great for everyone and gets even better.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>December 4th Week - Merry Christmas & development full speed ahead!</title>
   <link href="/2022/12/26/December-w4/"/>
   <updated>2022-12-26T00:00:00+09:00</updated>
   <id>/website/2022/12/26/December-w4</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CARD NOVA / GENERIC RPG WEEKLY REPORT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The launch of the Steam page for CARD NOVA HYPER has been going extremely well, having being covered by sites all across the globe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And finally I got the assets I need for GRI. I’ll reveal the new trailer later! Currently implementing all the sounds and the music system. GRI is going steady. I want to fix a bloating problem with the save system that has been around for a long time, so that might take some time and possibly introduce bugs, which scare me. But gotta do it now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I contacted Nintendo and I’m waiting for their reply…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is the time table for this week and last week (week 51 of 2022):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;2022 W:51 monster    : 27:01:00
2022 W:51 manager    :  0:52:00
2022 W:51 hrpg       : 16:46:00
2022 W:51 marketing  :  0:58:00
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Times have been great and progress on both games is going nicely. 2022 is about to end and I’m glad I got this far. I have had the goals of pitching the game to Nintendo and launching the Card game steam page for quite some time now, nice to see that I finally reached both stages. While CARD NOVA HYPER will only release in 2024, I have many plans for 2023. One of those should be GRI leaving early access next year. If the stars align, maybe GRI comes to Nintendo Switch in 2023? We will see!!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next time I write one of those is gonna be 2024!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>December 3rd week - Revealed new Steam Page!</title>
   <link href="/2022/12/19/December-w3/"/>
   <updated>2022-12-19T00:00:00+09:00</updated>
   <id>/website/2022/12/19/December-w3</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CARD NOVA / GENERIC RPG WEEKLY REPORT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I finally revealed the Steam page for Card Nova Hyper, the name of my deckbuilder RPG! 
https://store.steampowered.com/app/2197330/CARD_NOVA_HYPER/
The release date is set for 2024 and development is still in the early stages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, hopefully I’ll be able to reveal the new trailer for Generic RPG Idle before the year ends!
Unfortunately, my recent contractors have delayed things multiple things, so I think it will be revealed in January. After that I think I’ll be up to more waiting when pitchting to Nintendo.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is the time table for this week and last week (week 50 of 2022):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;2022 W:50 hrpg       :  2:44:00
2022 W:50 battle     :  6:55:00
2022 W:50 monster    : 38:04:00
2022 W:50 manager    :  0:13:00
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have spent a lot of time focusing on the card game (monster). All those delays related to GRI (Generic RPG Idle) are messing up my plans. I will have to take some time to replan how I want to proceed with GRI from now on, taking into account all the delays.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>December 2nd week - Working and Waiting Part 3</title>
   <link href="/2022/12/12/December-w2/"/>
   <updated>2022-12-12T00:00:00+09:00</updated>
   <id>/website/2022/12/12/December-w2</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;GENERIC RPG WEEKLY REPORT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I got the sound effects! Am now waiting for music and press release writing.
I will probably pitch Generic RPG Idle to Nintendo on December or January. Hope they reply fast.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is the time table for this week and last week (week 49 of 2022):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;2022 W:49 engine     : 46:33:00
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I spent 46 hours just hacking away at the engine. I managed to greatly optimize my code, but it’s hard to use all of the optimized code in Generic RPG Idle. I do think that for the next GRI update performance should increase a fair bit. Not sure when that next update will be as I’m doing a lot of waiting for other people and my plans will change depending on Nintendo’s reply. The engine will be used on my future games.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyways, let’s keep going!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>December 1st week - Working and Waiting Part 2</title>
   <link href="/2022/12/05/December-w1/"/>
   <updated>2022-12-05T00:00:00+09:00</updated>
   <id>/website/2022/12/05/December-w1</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;GENERIC RPG WEEKLY REPORT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Still waiting for the sound effects… [2]
This week, as a preparation for the future, I have started to see how I can optimize my engine.
I have optimized some stuff on GRI (and broke other things in the process…), so FPS in the next build should hopefully be a bit higher.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is the time table for this week and last week (week 48 of 2022):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;2022 W:48 gamejam    :  2:22:00
2022 W:48 manager    :  0:23:00
2022 W:48 hrpg       : 33:14:00
2022 W:48 monster    : 18:50:00
2022 W:48 feedback   :  0:00:00
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Productivity was very nice. Mainly because trying to optimize the rendering engine is really engaging. It’s really addictive to try to do it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s goo!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>November 4th week - Working and Waiting Part 2</title>
   <link href="/2022/11/28/November-w4/"/>
   <updated>2022-11-28T00:00:00+09:00</updated>
   <id>/website/2022/11/28/November-w4</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;GENERIC RPG WEEKLY REPORT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Still waiting for the sound effects… Also waiting for an animation for the card game.
I also took some time to work on a game jam! I couldn’t actually submit (first time in my life that I enter in a gamejam and don’t submit). The main reason is because I wanted to implement a very specific battle system and prioritized that more than the game jam. I didn’t even finish the game logic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next GRI update:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Sounds and music, new animations and effects&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;MAYBE: more unknown tab content&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is the time table for this week and last week (week 47 of 2022):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;2022 W:47 monster    :  4:59:00
2022 W:47 manager    :  2:09:00
2022 W:47 hrpg       : 21:50:00
2022 W:47 study      :  4:27:00
2022 W:47 gamejam    : 13:27:00
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Productivity was nice.
For a couple of the next weeks, I think the time I use on GRI (hrpg) will become a bit lower. I am currently preparing to send the game to Nintendo and I’ll wait a bit for their response.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s goo!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>November 3rd week - Working and Waiting</title>
   <link href="/2022/11/21/November-w3/"/>
   <updated>2022-11-21T00:00:00+09:00</updated>
   <id>/website/2022/11/21/November-w3</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;GENERIC RPG WEEKLY REPORT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The sound guy is working on the game and it is taking time.
Meanwhile, I just do some small fixes and additions in Generic RPG Idle.
As for the card game, I spent the whole weekend preparing the base material for an animation. It was a bit crazy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next GRI update:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Sounds and music, new animations and effects&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;MAYBE: more unknown tab content&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is the time table for this week and last week (week 46 of 2022):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;2022 W:46 manager    :  1:08:00
2022 W:46 hrpg       : 22:55:00
2022 W:46 monster    : 18:28:00
2022 W:46 study      :  0:20:00
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Productivity didn’t change much from last week. Spent less time studying and more time pixeling. It was the first time I spend over 10 hours on Aseprite. Hopefully it pays off soon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Best in life to all!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>November 2nd week - Aftermath!</title>
   <link href="/2022/11/14/November-w2/"/>
   <updated>2022-11-14T00:00:00+09:00</updated>
   <id>/website/2022/11/14/November-w2</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;GENERIC RPG WEEKLY REPORT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I worked on implementing some animations I had ordered from pixel artists into the game. It is still not done as there is a bit of programming backbone to make it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since one of the players has cleared all of the unknown tab content I feel like I want to increase the priority of adding more unknown tab content to the game. We’ll see how it goes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As for the card game, I spent time on the Steam page and researching some stuff. I should be announcing something next Month. Might get delayed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next update:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Sounds and music, new animations and effects&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;MAYBE: more unknown tab content&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The sound guy I found should start working on it today. It’s going to cost quite a bit of money but let’s see how it goes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The polish criteria is still this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How easily reusable is this improvement for other projects?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How fast can I make it?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Do I have a good reference to use when making the polish?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Does the polish look good on trailers?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Does the polish make the game easier to understand?
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;makes it easier for people who just started to understand the game&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;visualized that actions happened&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;how actions actually work&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How often will new players see this polish?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;how often will long-term players see this polish?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Is the polish making the game prettier but less enjoyable to play somehow?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is the time table for this week and last week (week 45 of 2022):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;2022 W:45 manager    :  0:15:00
2022 W:45 monster    : 18:10:00
2022 W:45 study      :  4:35:00
2022 W:45 hrpg       : 18:20:00
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Productivity is good, I think. Time spent in the card game (monster) and in GRI (hrpg) are around the same. I spent four hours studying indie game development process too, which will be nice for both the card game and my next titles. Hopefully.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Best in life to all!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>November 1st week - Halloween released!</title>
   <link href="/2022/11/07/November-w1/"/>
   <updated>2022-11-07T00:00:00+09:00</updated>
   <id>/website/2022/11/07/November-w1</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;GENERIC RPG WEEKLY REPORT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I released the halloween update. I didn’t advertise the event because I’m trying to focus more on long-term goals (getting the new GRI update going and start planning the next update) than short-term ones (making extra money). I’m thinking there might be only 1~3 updates until launch. I mean 1 update =&amp;gt; final update for release.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next update:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Sounds and music, new animations and effects&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;MAYBE: more unknown tab content&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The polish criteria is still this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How easily reusable is this improvement for other projects?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How fast can I make it?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Do I have a good reference to use when making the polish?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Does the polish look good on trailers?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Does the polish make the game easier to understand?
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;makes it easier for people who just started to understand the game&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;visualized that actions happened&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;how actions actually work&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How often will new players see this polish?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;how often will long-term players see this polish?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Is the polish making the game prettier but less enjoyable to play somehow?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But I found a sound guy and want to get it done.
So I don’t think I’ll be adding any additional effects other than what I have planned. Might enhance what is already there though. Maybe that’s more of sequel material though.
&lt;strong&gt;__&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;__&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;__&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;__&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;__&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;__&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;__&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;__&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;__&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;__&lt;/strong&gt;_&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is the time table for this week and last week (week 44 of 2022):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;2022 W:44 hrpg       : 21:15:00
2022 W:44 manager    :  1:08:00
2022 W:44 monster    : 18:25:00
2022 W:44 designer   :  0:16:00
2022 W:44 housework  :  0:19:00
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Productivity is okay but I have been playing Loop Hero which is a big time drain. It gave me some ideas about game structure (game has some nice game structure ideas though nothing ideal) but I don’t want to explore that direction too much right now. The monster project which is progressing nicely and I might have something to show for it in December!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also made a website lol a bit sooner than what I expected but it’s there. I’ll probably change the discord channel name to suit the new developer name I’ll be using. (Finally retiring “Pidroh”).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Best in life to all!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>October 4th week - Halloween is coming people!</title>
   <link href="/2022/10/31/October-w5/"/>
   <updated>2022-10-31T00:00:00+09:00</updated>
   <id>/website/2022/10/31/October-w5</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;GENERIC RPG WEEKLY REPORT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The halloweeen content is ready to be published! I’ll do it tonight I think, just to be sure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next update:
A) Boss, skills and equipment mods (related to blood mechanics)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Event announcement: https://store.steampowered.com/app/1858120/Generic_RPG_Idle/&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I decided to not put in music yet. I need to polish things up and make sure I’m not making anything annoying. I might wait until I have sound effects to put music in. And to make sound effects, I want to have a final version of what the game will play like. So I’m now trying to decide on how much I’ll prettify and animate the game. This is a hard decision for me because I don’t want to spend a long time doing this. So I’ll try to be very selective about what I polish. I guess the criteria should be:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How easily reusable is this improvement for other projects?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How fast can I make it?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Do I have a good reference to use when making the polish?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Does the polish look good on trailers?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Does the polish make the game easier to understand?
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;makes it easier for people who just started to understand the game&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;visualized that actions happened&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;how actions actually work&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How often will new players see this polish?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;how often will long-term players see this polish?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Is the polish making the game prettier but less enjoyable to play somehow?
&lt;strong&gt;__&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;__&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;__&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;__&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;__&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;__&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;__&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;__&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;__&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;__&lt;/strong&gt;_&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is the time table for this week and last week (week 42 of 2022):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;2022 W:42 hrpg       : 11:10:00
2022 W:42 manager    :  0:19:00
2022 W:42 company    :  1:31:00
2022 W:42 monster    : 14:45:00
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Productivity is down. Lately Netflix has been getting to me. And thinking about polishing Generic RPG Idle is a bit discouraging because it’s hard to make decisions. I don’t like some things about how the game looks right now and I want to fix it by remaking everything in pixel art which I absolutely WILL NOT do. Only for a complete sequel / spiritual successor. So things are a bit discouraging.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s gooo Halloweeeeeeeeeeeeeeen!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>October 4th week - Halloween is coming people!</title>
   <link href="/2022/10/24/October-w4/"/>
   <updated>2022-10-24T00:00:00+09:00</updated>
   <id>/website/2022/10/24/October-w4</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;GENERIC RPG WEEKLY REPORT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The halloweeen content is ready to be published! I’ll do it tonight I think, just to be sure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next update:
A) Boss, skills and equipment mods (related to blood mechanics)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Event announcement: https://store.steampowered.com/app/1858120/Generic_RPG_Idle/&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I decided to not put in music yet. I need to polish things up and make sure I’m not making anything annoying. I might wait until I have sound effects to put music in. And to make sound effects, I want to have a final version of what the game will play like. So I’m now trying to decide on how much I’ll prettify and animate the game. This is a hard decision for me because I don’t want to spend a long time doing this. So I’ll try to be very selective about what I polish. I guess the criteria should be:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How easily reusable is this improvement for other projects?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How fast can I make it?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Do I have a good reference to use when making the polish?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Does the polish look good on trailers?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Does the polish make the game easier to understand?
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;makes it easier for people who just started to understand the game&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;visualized that actions happened&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;how actions actually work&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How often will new players see this polish?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;how often will long-term players see this polish?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Is the polish making the game prettier but less enjoyable to play somehow?
&lt;strong&gt;__&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;__&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;__&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;__&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;__&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;__&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;__&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;__&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;__&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;__&lt;/strong&gt;_&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is the time table for this week and last week (week 42 of 2022):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;2022 W:42 hrpg       : 11:10:00
2022 W:42 manager    :  0:19:00
2022 W:42 company    :  1:31:00
2022 W:42 monster    : 14:45:00
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Productivity is down. Lately Netflix has been getting to me. And thinking about polishing Generic RPG Idle is a bit discouraging because it’s hard to make decisions. I don’t like some things about how the game looks right now and I want to fix it by remaking everything in pixel art which I absolutely WILL NOT do. Only for a complete sequel / spiritual successor. So things are a bit discouraging.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s gooo Halloweeeeeeeeeeeeeeen!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>October 3rd week - Halloween? And music </title>
   <link href="/2022/10/17/October-w3/"/>
   <updated>2022-10-17T00:00:00+09:00</updated>
   <id>/website/2022/10/17/October-w3</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;GENERIC RPG WEEKLY REPORT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The graphics update launched. Natural sales from Steam aren’t getting boosted as much as I thought. Maybe it didn’t change anything which is interesting. I’m a bit relieved it didn’t somehow make the game perform worse. Of course the data I have isn’t “scientific” so I’m speculating on small data, but never the less, it did not make any significant change in revenue for better or for worse for natural Steam traffic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But I guess Reddit comments are getting boosted…? Maybe…? Maybe not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is all a bit surprising. Perhaps I should stick to minimalistic games and focus more on better systems instead of pixel art. Then once I arrive at something I love, I can create a bigger budget game and go full power. Food for thought.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am preparing some halloween content. And also music.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next update:
A) Halloween content
B) Music maybe&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is the time table for this week and last week (week 41 of 2022):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;2022 W:41 hrpg       : 28:44:00
2022 W:41 manager    :  2:05:00
2022 W:41 monster    : 11:15:00
2022 W:41 company    : 10:33:00
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Productivity is still nice. I’m back to allocating time to the card game which is plenty of fun to think about too. But it’s getting a bit blocked by company documents.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s gooo Halloweeeeeeeeeeeeeeen!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>October 2nd week - Remaking the UI V </title>
   <link href="/2022/10/10/October-w2/"/>
   <updated>2022-10-10T00:00:00+09:00</updated>
   <id>/website/2022/10/10/October-w2</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;GENERIC RPG WEEKLY REPORT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I released a small beta for the changes. I got some nice feedback and made some adjustments. Things SEEM fine. No bugs coming up yet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next update:
A) Equipment screen update
B) Battle screen update
C) Chapter 2
D) QOL&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The boost from 10 reviews was dying but then I posted the game on feedback friday asking for feedback on the beta. Some folks ignored the beta instructions part and just bought the game straight away. I think the (positive) label is also improving quality of when I post the game for people to see. People know the game isn’t broken because of the positive reviews and all. This is just a theory, but since conversion rate is probably increased, every person I send to Steam is a high quality visit which makes Steam want to promote the page a little bit. And since conversion rate is also up when Steam promotes the page, the boost is bigger. What I want to say is that the 10 reviews thing really creates a cummulative positive effect for everything you do Steam related.
&lt;strong&gt;__&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;__&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;__&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;__&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;__&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;__&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;__&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;__&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;__&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;__&lt;/strong&gt;_&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is the time table for this week and last week (week 40 of 2022):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;2022 W:40 hrpg       : 36:05:00
2022 W:40 company    : 12:26:00
2022 W:40 manager    :  2:15:00
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PRODUCTIVITY IS BACK BABY! Didn’t even notice it. I think it’s because I got pretty engaged in finish up the update. Also I finished a big part of the documents of registering the company. It already exists and all. After I get the tax information set up I’ll transfer my Steam games to the company.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Goooooooooooo!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>October 1st week - Remaking the UI IV </title>
   <link href="/2022/10/04/October-w1/"/>
   <updated>2022-10-04T00:00:00+09:00</updated>
   <id>/website/2022/10/04/October-w1</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;GENERIC RPG WEEKLY REPORT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fixing bugs and other small details while finishing up the battle UI. Not sure if I release the update in the middle of October or if I cook it up for November. Will try to go for October.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next update:
A) Equipment screen update
B) Battle screen update
B) Chapter 2 maybe. Chapter 3 maybe?
C) ???????????? Icons to the UI? Notifications on tabs?  (partially)
D) Cooking?? (unlikely)
D) Offline progress (unlikely)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I GOT TO 10 REVIEWS!! Sales and wishlists get a big boost. Let’s see how the new graphics will affect those numbers.
&lt;strong&gt;__&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;__&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;__&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;__&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;__&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;__&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;__&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;__&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;__&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;__&lt;/strong&gt;_
&lt;strong&gt;__&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;__&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;__&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;__&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;__&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;__&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;__&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;__&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;__&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;__&lt;/strong&gt;_&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is the time table for this week and last week (week 39 of 2022):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;2022 W:39 hrpg       : 25:03:00
2022 W:39 manager    :  0:17:00
2022 W:39 company    :  8:36:00
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Productivity is a bit back up. I spent 8 hours on the burocracy of opening a company though. I should become company president in a couple of days lol.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Goooooooooooo!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>September 4th week - Remaking the UI III </title>
   <link href="/2022/09/27/September-w4/"/>
   <updated>2022-09-27T00:00:00+09:00</updated>
   <id>/website/2022/09/27/September-w4</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;GENERIC RPG WEEKLY REPORT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The battle UI is almost done. There are just some small features and animations that need to be redone. I’m starting to get excited about this. The game just feels different. Can’t wait to get this to players.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next update:
A) Equipment screen update
B) Battle screen update
B) Chapter 2 maybe. Chapter 3 maybe?
C) ???????????? Icons to the UI? Notifications on tabs?  (partially)
D) Cooking?? (unlikely)
D) Offline progress (unlikely)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am now at 8 reviews! Only two more people to get to 10! 
&lt;strong&gt;__&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;__&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;__&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;__&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;__&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;__&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;__&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;__&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;__&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;__&lt;/strong&gt;_
&lt;strong&gt;__&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;__&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;__&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;__&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;__&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;__&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;__&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;__&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;__&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;__&lt;/strong&gt;_&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is the time table for this week and last week (week 38 of 2022):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;2022 W:38 burocracy  :  0:48:00
2022 W:38 hrpg       : 23:05:00
2022 W:38 monster    :  1:33:00
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Productivity is still a bit down lately. Wonder why. Still, I have a full time job… Maybe my productivity was just too high before?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyways, I’ll keep going!! Hopefully this visual update boosts sales significantly.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>September 3rd week - Remaking the UI II </title>
   <link href="/2022/09/22/September-w3/"/>
   <updated>2022-09-22T00:00:00+09:00</updated>
   <id>/website/2022/09/22/September-w3</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;GENERIC RPG WEEKLY REPORT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The battle UI is still going, slowly. The game is slowly coming into shape. The story is giving me trouble because there are a lot of stages and the backgrounds have to be set manually. The new animations for the main character should be coming in later this week. No idea if I’ll make a new trailer or not. Sound effects will probably come at a different update so maybe I should wait for sound effects before updating the trailer? Or just create a quick 15 second trailer myself? I don’t know what to do. The look of the game is going to change a lot but I don’t really want to do two trailers. Might not have a choice though.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next update:
A) Equipment screen update
B) Battle screen update
B) Chapter 2 maybe. Chapter 3 maybe?
C) ???????????? Icons to the UI? Notifications on tabs? 
D) Cooking??
D) Offline progress (maybe?)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am now at 8 reviews! Only two more people to get to 10! 
&lt;strong&gt;__&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;__&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;__&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;__&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;__&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;__&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;__&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;__&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;__&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;__&lt;/strong&gt;_
&lt;strong&gt;__&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;__&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;__&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;__&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;__&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;__&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;__&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;__&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;__&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;__&lt;/strong&gt;_&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is the time table for this week and last week (week 37 of 2022):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;2022 W:37 hrpg       : 15:35:00
2022 W:37 manager    :  1:11:00
2022 W:37 marketing  :  0:42:00
2022 W:37 burocracy  :  2:59:00
2022 W:37 monster    :  3:40:00
2022 W:37 business   :  1:55:00
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Productivity went down last week. Lately I have been hooked in a show called Ozark and I haven’t been so motivated to work in the game. Still, not the end of the world considering I have a full-time job too.
I went to Tokyo Game Show which was great. I also got corona but had almost no symptoms so no problem in that front. Still no idea on what to get ready for the Halloween update. I might separate the UI update from the Halloween update. Not too sure on that one. Depends on how long I take to complete the UI update.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyways, I’ll keep going!! Hopefully this UI updates boosts sales significantly.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>September 2nd week - Remaking the UI </title>
   <link href="/2022/09/12/September-w2/"/>
   <updated>2022-09-12T00:00:00+09:00</updated>
   <id>/website/2022/09/12/September-w2</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;GENERIC RPG WEEKLY REPORT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Still improving the UI. I’m happy with the equipment UI remake I made. The battle UI is giving me trouble because of the addition of backgrounds. Backgrounds are kinda disturbing the current contrast of the scenes. I struggled quite a bit to make the palette something that doesn’t fight too much with the UI, but I think I managed to find a good balance. There is still a long way to go to finish remaking the UI. I say this not because I know what those tasks are but because it looks bad right now. Another problem is that my artist is busy, so things are going slow in that front too. I can’t wait to have animations in the game though.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think the next update might come during Halloween? And maybe be halloween themed. So I’m guessing the end of October? Not sure. That would probably give me enough time to remake the trailer. That’s whole other issue all together. Not sure if I should try to find a new person to make the trailer or use the same person as before. I’m not happy with the previous person but then I’m not sure if I can find someone much better either…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next update:
A) Equipment screen update
B) Chapter 2 maybe. Chapter 3 maybe?
C) ???????????? Icons to the UI? Notifications on tabs? 
D) Cooking??
D) Offline progress (maybe?)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not much progress on review count. 
&lt;strong&gt;__&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;__&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;__&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;__&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;__&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;__&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;__&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;__&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;__&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;__&lt;/strong&gt;_
&lt;strong&gt;__&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;__&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;__&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;__&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;__&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;__&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;__&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;__&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;__&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;__&lt;/strong&gt;_&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is the time table for this week and last week (week 35 &amp;amp; 36 of 2022):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;2022 W:35 hrpg       :  36:13:00
2022 W:35 monster    :  6:45:00
2022 W:35 burocracy  :  1:57:00
2022 W:35 manager    :  0:29:00
2022 W:35 marketing  :  0:11:00
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;2022 W:36 hrpg       : 26:47:00
2022 W:36 monster    :  2:24:00
2022 W:36 burocracy  :  1:44:00
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Things have slowed down on the monster card game because I’m waiting for artists. So right now most of the the time in that project is related to interacting with artists instead of programming.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>September 1st week - After the update...?</title>
   <link href="/2022/09/02/September-w1/"/>
   <updated>2022-09-02T00:00:00+09:00</updated>
   <id>/website/2022/09/02/September-w1</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;GENERIC RPG WEEKLY REPORT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m getting closer to 10 reviews but still far. Lately I have decided to improve the UI of the game. More like a complete remake of what the game looks like right now hahahaha. I want to remake mainly the equipment screen and the battle screen. I don’t know how the update of the battle screen is gonna go though.  There are too many weapons and paying a artist to animate all the weapons and skills would be complicated. I’m still thinking through this. Wish I could do a kickstarter, but a kickstarter for an idle game is something I have never heard of before. Maybe I should be a pioneer?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next update:
A) Equipment screen update
B) Chapter 2 maybe. Chapter 3 maybe?
C) ???????????? Icons to the UI? Notifications on tabs? 
D) Cooking??
D) Offline progress (maybe?)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I should be done remaking the equipment UI fairly soon. Then I need to stop and decide on what to do next. I really want to do notification on tabs and other QOL stuff. I feel like that should be done before I move on to remaking the battle graphics. I’m giving a wild guess here, but I think Generic RPG Idle should stay in early access for around four to six months? So I can really improve the experience before launch. Honestly I wasn’t expecting to develop for so long. If I somehow manage to remake the battle screen BEFORE 2022 ends, I will try to pitch the game to Nintendo. Hopefully by then I will have 10 reviews?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is the time table for this week (week 34 of 2022):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;2022 W:34 hrpg       : 28:00:00
2022 W:34 monster    : 12:58:00
2022 W:34 manager    :  1:27:00
2022 W:34 marketing  :  1:13:00
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Things are progressing. I want to reveal the Steam page for the card game soon. Maybe in one or two months? Maybe less.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>August 4th Week - Rituals and Magic released!!</title>
   <link href="/2022/08/25/August-w4/"/>
   <updated>2022-08-25T00:00:00+09:00</updated>
   <id>/website/2022/08/25/August-w4</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;GENERIC RPG WEEKLY REPORT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I released the content update and the game is up for sale. I’m still really far from 10 reviews. I’m a bit lost on what I’m going to do next. I need to think about the second major update to the game. Also need to figure out if I want to translate the game or not. I think I want to have Chinese, Japanese and German support for sure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next update:
A) sound effects lol possibly music
B) Chapter 2 maybe. Chapter 3 maybe?
C) ???????????? Icons to the UI? Notifications on tabs? Actual animations during battle?
D) Cooking??
D) Offline progress (maybe?)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is the time table for this week (week 33 of 2022):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;2022 W:33 hrpg       : 32:24:00
2022 W:33 monster    :  9:12:00
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I haven’t really double checked those times not sure if they are correct. We’ll see how it goes. The card game prototype is advancing in the shadows. I have burned a lot of money on artists already for that game lol&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>August 3rd Week - Preparing the Update IV</title>
   <link href="/2022/08/15/August-w3/"/>
   <updated>2022-08-15T00:00:00+09:00</updated>
   <id>/website/2022/08/15/August-w3</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;GENERIC RPG WEEKLY REPORT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am done with the update content. I’ll update the beta builds to try and catch more bugs and get going with the browser beta on Reddit. Maybe I can release the update next week? I don’t know. I’m also preparing a new trailer for the game. Last week was a bit stressful, as releases / updates usually are. But we’ll see how it goes. Hopefully the update goes well. I still need to update a bunch of stuff on the Steam page for it though&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Update 1 should have:
A) Everything included in the beta right now unless I am forced to remove something
B) A little more arcania
C) A little more exploration
D) New items and skills&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While update 2 MIGHT have:
A) Visual effects and sound effects lol possibly music
B) Chapter 2 maybe
C) Offline progress (maybe maybe)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is the time table for this week (week 32 of 2022):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;2022 W:32 hrpg       : 52:51:00
2022 W:32 marketing  :  0:05:00
2022 W:32 monster    :  4:06:00
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today was my most “productive” week, but I’m pretty burned out. I want to release this update and take a mental rest. Not sure if I’ll actually do that though… Lol. Oh well. Let’s keep going! Just a bit more until I can release this!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>August 2nd Week - Preparing the Update III</title>
   <link href="/2022/08/09/August-w2/"/>
   <updated>2022-08-09T00:00:00+09:00</updated>
   <id>/website/2022/08/09/August-w2</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;GENERIC RPG WEEKLY REPORT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After adding a bunch of content to the Unknown tab and adding the exploration mode for Lu (old name You), I decided to run a beta test. This is mainly because I’m worried about how players will receive the new system. The beta has been running for a while but nobody has said anything. Maybe the new exploration system doesn’t really make much of a difference? I don’t know.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Update 1 should have:
A) Everything included in the beta unless I am forced to remove something
B) A little more arcania
C) A little more exploration
D) New items and skills (maybe)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While update 2 MIGHT have:
A) Visual effects and sound effects lol possibly music
B) Chapter 2 maybe
C) Offline progress (maybe maybe)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is the time table for this week (week 31 of 2022):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;2022 W:31 hrpg       : 37:51:00
2022 W:31 manager    :  0:49:00
2022 W:31 marketing  :  3:51:00
2022 W:31 monster    : 16:24:00
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I ended up not recording game designer tasks separately so a lot of thinking stuff ended up going into GRI development (hrpg), alongside getting ready for the beta and etc. As for monster, the card game, most of the time there was spent looking through artist submissions and giving instructions to the artist I plan to work with. The artist is not for card / monster design, but for character design. Let’s see how that project goes.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>August 1st Week - Preparing the Update II</title>
   <link href="/2022/08/01/August-w1/"/>
   <updated>2022-08-01T00:00:00+09:00</updated>
   <id>/website/2022/08/01/August-w1</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;GENERIC RPG WEEKLY REPORT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today was a hard week that paid off. So I decided to change directions, like I said last week. At first the new system was feeling kinda boring. I felt discouraged and my mind started thinking of other things. But I just kept adding stuff to the system, adjusting and fixing the problems. It is not perfect, but I feel like I managed to breakthrough the problems I was seeing. I still need to tweak and adjust more, but it’s going well I believe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Update 1 might have:
A) Visual effects
B) New exploration system
C) more Unknown tab content
D) Improved selling (maybe)
E) New items and skills (maybe)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There isn’t a lot of time so I’m not sure on how much I can include :( I do want to include improved selling even if the simplest possibility (automatically selling non-magic items)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While update 2 MIGHT have:
A) Visual effects and sound effects lol possibly music
B) Chapter 2 maybe
C) Offline progress and XP cap removal (maybe maybe)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is the time table for this week (week 30 of 2022):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;2022 W:30 hrpg       : 32:42:00
2022 W:30 manager    :  1:08:00
2022 W:30 marketing  :  0:43:00
2022 W:30 designer   :  0:15:00
2022 W:30 burocracy  :  0:05:00
2022 W:30 monster    : 11:51:00
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Those hours are a bit too good so I think I must have messed up the recording of them. Not sure, I did double check. About play testing the monster card game, there are appears to be some nice services for that. Found this one: https://www.reddit.com/r/gamedev/comments/wb3kb7/found_a_really_great_platform_to_get_feedback_on/ I probably can’t use that one early on since it is only for polished vertical slices, but still. I guess I’ll find a way to get nice amounts of play testing somehow.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>July 4th Week - Preparing the Update</title>
   <link href="/2022/07/25/July-w4/"/>
   <updated>2022-07-25T00:00:00+09:00</updated>
   <id>/website/2022/07/25/July-w4</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;GENERIC RPG WEEKLY REPORT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I decided to change directions. I decided on deprioritizing the story. So I won’t work on the story much until I can improve some of the things I’m not happy about in the game. Isabel’s story is a very small part of the GRI experience and You’s gameplay (I’m thinking of changing the name to Yuu) is pretty much the main meat of the game. I want to prioritize that first. I think that will result in a more engaging game and lay the fundation for improving both active gameplay and idle gameplay.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Right now I think that update 1 MIGHT have:
A) Visual effects
B) New exploration system
C) more Unknown tab content
D) Improved selling (maybe)
E) New items and skills (maybe)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While update 2 MIGHT have:
A) Visual effects and sound effects lol possibly music
B) Chapter 2 maybe
C) Offline progress and XP cap removal (maybe maybe)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is the time table for this week (week 28 of 2022):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;2022 W:29 hrpg       : 23:58:00
2022 W:29 manager    :  5:37:00
2022 W:29 marketing  :  0:19:00
2022 W:29 hstory     :  0:01:00
2022 W:29 designer   :  2:24:00
2022 W:29 monster    :  9:10:00
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nice hours. I decided to increase the time I spend on the monster card game to around 8 hours. After adding very basic enemy behavior, the card game is ALMOST playable but full of bugs. Maybe I can get something playable in a week or two? Looking forward to that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It doesn’t have idle elements so I’m unsure on how I will get players at an early stage. I was thinking about keeping playtests private until the game is more polished. We will see.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>July 3rd Week - Steam Early Access released!!</title>
   <link href="/2022/07/18/July-w3/"/>
   <updated>2022-07-18T00:00:00+09:00</updated>
   <id>/website/2022/07/18/July-w3</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;GENERIC RPG WEEKLY REPORT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This week has been filled with bug fixes. Some of them I could have somehow caught beforehand, some that I just had to release and bite the bullet. I implemented 3 visual effects for the update. I’m not sure if I’ll do audio too or not. Maybe audio will come in update 2. The game made more money than what I was expecting, though I didn’t actually try to predict how much money it would make. It is by no means a hit, but it is doing much better than my previous Steam release 7 years ago, Daily Espada. I had one bad review but after addressing his problems he changed the review, which felt great.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Right now I think that update 1 MIGHT have:
A) Visual effects
B) more Unknown tab content
C) chapter 2 story complete
D) New items and skills (maybe)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While update 2 MIGHT have:
A) Visual effects and sound effects lol possibly music
B) Chapter 3 half or complete
C) Offline progress and XP cap removal (maybe maybe)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is the time table for this week (week 28 of 2022):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;2022 W:28 hrpg       : 29:06:00
2022 W:28 manager    :  1:20:00
2022 W:28 marketing  :  1:49:00
2022 W:28 gamestudy  :  0:19:00
2022 W:28 monster    :  6:54:00
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Steam release kinda got me in a groove so I had some nice hours this week. The card game prototype is still going slowwwwww. I feel like I’m overengineering it by writing organized code, not sure if it will be worth it in the long run or not. We will see.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyways, feels great to finally have a new released game again, that people think it is worth their money. Gonna keep going!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>July 2nd Week - Getting ready for Early Access release (3)</title>
   <link href="/2022/07/11/July-w2/"/>
   <updated>2022-07-11T00:00:00+09:00</updated>
   <id>/website/2022/07/11/July-w2</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;GENERIC RPG WEEKLY REPORT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I finished up what one part of the addition to the new resource management system (Unknown tab). I also wrote all cutscenes of chapter 2, but only half of it is implemented in the early access release. I still need to integrate the rest of the cutscenes of chapter 2 in a later update. Right now I am changing the way I handle sprites in the game so I don’t have to add them manually to the game code. By automating this, it will be simpler to add new sprites and also simpler to add Spine animations to the game.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Spine will be my main animation tool for effects which is a departure because all my previous games that had a lot of effects (Daily Espada, Jobchanger Brigade, even my older games like Dragon Sky Rush) were all heavily dependant on particle systems. Hopefully this will mean more polished games? Hehehe, who knows. Which unfortunately means I am switching the focus from content to polishing, at least for a while. This is the first time I’m focusing on the appearance / marketability of the game. Since I’m creating a lot of systems from scratch, expanding my “engine” to have better integration with Spine is a good long-term investment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I think after early access, I’ll do a big update that will have:
A) lots of visual effects and sound effects lol possibly music
B) more Unknown tab content
C) chapter 2 story complete&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are also some small bugs that I need to investigate regarding noblesse and Mystic Elf, but I am afraid of updating the current Steam build and breaking things before the release, so I will fix them at a later date :( :(&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I might also revamp the upgrade system but maybe I’ll leave that for a future update.
&lt;strong&gt;__&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;__&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;__&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;__&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;__&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;__&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;__&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;__&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;__&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;__&lt;/strong&gt;_
&lt;strong&gt;__&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;__&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;__&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;__&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;__&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;__&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;__&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;__&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;__&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;__&lt;/strong&gt;_&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is the time table for this week (week 27 of 2022):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;2022 W:27 hrpg       : 19:08:00
2022 W:27 manager    :  0:37:00
2022 W:27 marketing  :  1:44:00
2022 W:27 hcontent   :  2:17:00
2022 W:27 designer   :  1:45:00
2022 W:27 monster    :  6:24:00
2022 W:27 hstory     :  1:30:00
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These hours are good, considering I was busy for my birthday yesterday. I am splitting content between hstory and hcontent, so around 3 hours is nice. The card game prototype (Monster) is not progressing as fast as I hoped. The drag-and-drop oriented UI changes a lot from how I was handling UI in Generic RPG Idle. But once I get through that it should move faster. I’m still limitting myself to 5 hours (it goes to 6 and half because I lose track of time, but I force myself to stop once I realize it). I don’t know if I’ll increase the time I spend on this side project or not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyways, let’s keep going! TOMORROW IS THE STEAM RELEASE!!!!!!!!!!! (I think)&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>July 1st Week - Getting ready for Early Access release (2)</title>
   <link href="/2022/07/04/July-w1/"/>
   <updated>2022-07-04T00:00:00+09:00</updated>
   <id>/website/2022/07/04/July-w1</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I am currently expanding more on the new resource management system. I think I’ll release the Early Access version next 12 of July. Two days after my birthday lol. I do feel a bit lost now though. Too many things running in my mind… I feel that if I keep polishing this game, I could release it on consoles. At the same time, I also feel like I need to finish it up and move on to different games. It gives me a headache everytime I think about it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can try the game here: https://pidroh.github.io/GenericRPGIdle/&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is the time table for this week (week 26 of 2022):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;2022 W:26 hrpg       : 15:23:00
2022 W:26 manager    :  1:17:00
2022 W:26 marketing  :  0:46:00
2022 W:26 designer   :  1:05:00
2022 W:26 monster    :  7:22:00
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Work is also progressing on my new card game prototype. This week wasn’t so productive, met some friends and got hooked up on the new soccer anime. But still, 22 hours of development isn’t so bad.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>June 4th Week - Getting ready for Early Access release</title>
   <link href="/2022/06/27/June-w4/"/>
   <updated>2022-06-27T00:00:00+09:00</updated>
   <id>/website/2022/06/27/June-w4</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I have decided on a Steam release date for the game. Haven’t announced it yet because I’m not sure if I can make it D: but I think I can, unless some horrible problem comes up. This week I wrote some story for chapter 2 (I should have done this sooner). I wanted to release the Early Access version with the entirety of chapter 2, but I am not sure I can make it. Which means that early access might launch with half of chapter 2. I have two reasons for that:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1) I did some major rebalancing of the game’s Soul Crush system last week, to test that stuff I need some new simple dev tools
2) The game had some issues for people with big screens and I added that last week
3) The steam page still has screens and trailer from the last version. I might do something about this, not sure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I decide to rebalance the game now because I want people to be able to import their saves. The rebalance means that advance people will lose their Soul Crush / Challenge Area progress. Figured it was better do that sooner than later.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can try the game here: https://pidroh.github.io/GenericRPGIdle/&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is the time table for this week (week 25 of 2022):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;2022 W:25 manager    :  1:50:00
2022 W:25 marketing  :  1:58:00
2022 W:25 hrpg       : 24:09:00
2022 W:25 hstory     :  3:53:00
2022 W:25 design     :  1:08:00
2022 W:25 monster    :  5:58:00
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Those hours are nice. Anyways, me and my SO did break up but the relationship was decaying, so that was good in the long run, I believe. Anyways, this week I’ll continue making some debugging tools and make what content I can out of chapter 2. The Steam page overhaul might come later, on the first big update of the game.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It took a long time to release what was supposed to be a very small prototype for some game mechanics… I’m glad I did decide on a deadline for it, because the way I’m working in the game, I could keep developing the game forever. Let us keep going strong!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>June 3rd Week - Steam Next Fest is gone</title>
   <link href="/2022/06/20/June-w3/"/>
   <updated>2022-06-20T00:00:00+09:00</updated>
   <id>/website/2022/06/20/June-w3</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I release the first build of the game with the new subsystem. It is a resource generation &amp;amp; upgrade crafting system? I guess that is how you could call it. I still need to add more content to it though.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;AND STEAM NEXT FEST IS GONE! I mean, kinda, this is the last day. Honestly… Things are complicated. The average Steam player (or at least the audience present at the Steam Next Festivals) isn’t really the same audience as incremental games lol I might write more about this later. But I did learn a lot from the festival!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can try the game here: https://pidroh.github.io/GenericRPGIdle/&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is the time table for this week (week 24 of 2022):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;2022 W:24 hrpg       : 29:02:00
2022 W:24 manager    :  0:55:00
2022 W:24 marketing  :  0:59:00
2022 W:24 hcontent   :  3:52:00
2022 W:24 designer   :  0:49:00
2022 W:24 monster    :  6:55:00
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My hours were pretty high this week because I didn’t go out at all during the weekend. My SO is taking distance and I think we might break up soon hahahaha :( anyways, the next milestone is the Steam Early Access release!!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>June 2nd Week - The Road to Steam Next Fest (VII)</title>
   <link href="/2022/06/13/June-w2/"/>
   <updated>2022-06-13T00:00:00+09:00</updated>
   <id>/website/2022/06/13/June-w2</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Steam Next Fest is tomorrow! And I already messed up lol. On Steam Next Fest you can stream twice. I set one Stream to the wrong time and realizing I couldn’t change the time, I deleted the stream. And Steam won’t let me remake it. :( so I’ll only stream once. This week I have worked a lot on another subsystem that I haven’t talked much about because it’s a bit weird to explain. No idea how to call it lol.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can try the game here: https://pidroh.github.io/GenericRPGIdle/&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is the time table for this week (week 22 of 2022):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;2022 W:23 hrpg       : 27:02:00
2022 W:23 manager    :  2:02:00
2022 W:23 marketing  :  0:04:00
2022 W:23 monster    :  5:08:00
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m leaning towards working on some other systems before working again on weapon practice. If anyone who reads this wants to try out the current weapon system, do let me know.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>June 1st Week - The Road to Steam Next Fest (VI)</title>
   <link href="/2022/06/06/June-w1/"/>
   <updated>2022-06-06T00:00:00+09:00</updated>
   <id>/website/2022/06/06/June-w1</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Steam Next Fest starts in one week!!! And the weapon practice system isn’t as fun as I had hoped :( not sure if I’ll release the system as it is and try to get feedback on it or if I’ll just try to improve it before release.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can try the game here: https://pidroh.github.io/GenericRPGIdle/&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is the time table for this week (week 22 of 2022):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;2022 W:22 manager    :  1:54:00
2022 W:22 marketing  :  1:16:00
2022 W:22 hrpg       : 30:28:00
2022 W:22 designer   :  0:35:00
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m leaning towards working on some other systems before working again on weapon practice. If anyone who reads this wants to try out the current weapon system, do let me know.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>May 5th Week - The Road to Steam Next Fest (V)</title>
   <link href="/2022/05/30/May-w5/"/>
   <updated>2022-05-30T00:00:00+09:00</updated>
   <id>/website/2022/05/30/May-w5</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Just coding the new weapon practice system. Not much to add… Steam Next Fest starts in exactly two weeks! Maybe I’ll release the first version of the new weapon practice system then? Just make sure to say it is not complete. Not sure if it will be in a good state by then, but we’ll see.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can try the game here: https://pidroh.github.io/GenericRPGIdle/&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is the time table for this week (week 21 of 2022):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;2022 W:21 hrpg       : 35:41:00
2022 W:21 manager    :  0:00:00
2022 W:21 marketing  :  1:32:00
2022 W:21 designer   :  1:34:00
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The hours are much better than last week. Guess I had a good productive weekend to help boost that. But I did get burned out a bit and didn’t do anything Sunday night. Called my gradma back in Brazil… I’m such a terrible grandson though :( was supposed to call on her birthday but just kept postponing it… Felt guilty.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>May 4th Week - The Road to Steam Next Fest (IV)</title>
   <link href="/2022/05/24/May-w4/"/>
   <updated>2022-05-24T00:00:00+09:00</updated>
   <id>/website/2022/05/24/May-w4</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Focused a bit more on polish and then went back to coding the weapon practice system. The system is starting to take shape. I’m now considering if I should update my Steam page before Steam Next Fest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can try the game here: https://pidroh.github.io/GenericRPGIdle/&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is the time table for this week (week 20 of 2022):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;2022 W:20 hrpg       : 23:39:00
2022 W:20 marketing  :  1:37:00
2022 W:20 designer   :  0:47:00
2022 W:20 playtest   :  0:45:00
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The hours are okay? Don’t know if something happened specifically. Anyways, guess I’ll keep going… Really unsure if I focus on the Steam page or just focus on getting more content into the game. :(&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>May 3rd Week - The Road to Steam Next Fest (III)</title>
   <link href="/2022/05/16/May-w3/"/>
   <updated>2022-05-16T00:00:00+09:00</updated>
   <id>/website/2022/05/16/May-w3</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I was going to add more polish to the demo but ended up coding a new system lol but I’ll reevaluate stuff to polish from tomorrow. I also tried posting a video devlog on the incremental sub reddit but that wasn’t such a good idea. The video is too boring if you don’t edit it and all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can try the game here: https://pidroh.github.io/GenericRPGIdle/&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is the time table for this week (week 19 of 2022):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;2022 W:19 hrpg       : 31:48:00
2022 W:19 manager    :  0:18:00
2022 W:19 marketing  :  0:05:00
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The hours are nice. But the new system that I started coding is being a seed to stress. It’s one small system that is supposed to be part of a bigger system which also relates to the future games I can make. This makes me think about a thousand things. I’m a bit discouraged right now about the game and keep stressing myself out thinking about working on other games.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>May 2nd Week - The Road to Steam Next Fest (II)</title>
   <link href="/2022/05/09/May-w2/"/>
   <updated>2022-05-09T00:00:00+09:00</updated>
   <id>/website/2022/05/09/May-w2</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I did release the new story this Friday, which I didn’t think would happen! So that is nice. Right now I’m adding equipment to support different types of builds (counter-attack, magic, extreme speed, extreme attack). This will add some build variation and complexity to the game. After that is done, I’ll try to introduce complexity a bit better by limiting what players can see at the start of the game. Right now very complex pieces of equipment can drop in the very first battle. While fun, that can be daunting. After that I think I’ll just polish the demo.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can try the game here: https://pidroh.github.io/GenericRPGIdle/&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is the time table for this week (week 18 of 2022):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;2022 W:18 hrpg       : 30:28:00
2022 W:18 marketing  :  0:52:00
2022 W:18 burocracy  :  0:29:00
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Same 30 hours as last week. Nothing to complain here. It was a big holiday in Japan though, this kinda shows that having more free time doesn’t necessarily result in more hours being put to good use. :( which is a bit sad.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyways, Steam Next Fest it is. Already sent the first build of the demo for review, but they are taking a while so the demo might have a problem in it… Hope not.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>May 1st Week - The Road to Steam Next Fest</title>
   <link href="/2022/05/03/May-w1/"/>
   <updated>2022-05-03T00:00:00+09:00</updated>
   <id>/website/2022/05/03/May-w1</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I managed to fix the Steam save issues I was having!! Thank God!
This week I have been grinding away at all the problems of the new story cutscenes. And there are a lot of small problems… Maybe by next week I can get this new content out? Possibly not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can try the game here: https://pidroh.github.io/GenericRPGIdle/&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is the time table for this week (week 17 of 2022):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;2022 W:17 hrpg       : 30:01:00
2022 W:17 marketing  :  0:37:00
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Got a nice amount of programming, but I skipped some other weekly tasks I have. I used to do a design re-evaluation every Saturday, but I’m thinking of changing when I do that. And besides, now that I’m focusing on content it feels less necessary…?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just a month until Steam Next Fest D:&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>April 4th Week - The Road to Steam (II)</title>
   <link href="/2022/04/26/April-w4/"/>
   <updated>2022-04-26T00:00:00+09:00</updated>
   <id>/website/2022/04/26/April-w4</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Got some Steam feedback and already fixed it. Then found that saves are getting broken lol. And struggling to fix it. I added set support so I should have the foundation for the new content. I have also written 11 new cutscenes for the game. Still haven’t added them though.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can try the game here: https://pidroh.github.io/GenericRPGIdle/&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is the time table for this week (week 16 of 2022):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;2022 W:16 hrpg       : 30:27:00
2022 W:16 burocracy  :  0:04:00
2022 W:16 manager    :  0:49:00
2022 W:16 marketing  :  0:54:00
2022 W:16 designer   :  0:41:00
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This week was even better than before. Right now gonna keep hacking away at Steam issues while integrating the new story cutscenes.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>April 3rd Week - The Road to Steam</title>
   <link href="/2022/04/18/April-w3/"/>
   <updated>2022-04-18T00:00:00+09:00</updated>
   <id>/website/2022/04/18/April-w3</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Launched the playtest on Steam! Added animations to the game, revamped the UI, redid a bunch of UI stuff. The game should look and feel better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can try the game here: https://pidroh.github.io/GenericRPGIdle/&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is the time table for this week (week 15 of 2022):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;2022 W:15 hrpg       :  26:38:00
2022 W:15 marketing  :  0:18:00
2022 W:15 manager    :  0:18:00
2022 W:15 designer   :  1:04:00
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This week was remarkably better than the last on. Nothing in particular to comment on. I am now adding back ‘equipment set’ support. This will be important in adding more content to the game as players will need to use different builds. Right now optimizing speed and using pierce spells is the dominant strategy, which I want to diversify from before the early access release.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>April 2nd Week - The Grind (II)</title>
   <link href="/2022/04/11/April-w2/"/>
   <updated>2022-04-11T00:00:00+09:00</updated>
   <id>/website/2022/04/11/April-w2</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Added some popups, did some stuff with keyboard support, reorganized the beginning of the game a bit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can try the game here: https://pidroh.github.io/GenericRPGIdle/&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is the time table for this week (week 14 of 2022):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;2022 W:14 marketing  :  1:02:00
2022 W:14 hrpg       : 14:22:00
2022 W:14 manager    :  2:48:00
2022 W:14 designer   :  2:09:00
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This week… Was bad. My worst week in a long time lol. I guess the weekend wasn’t productive at all. And the week days also were not the best. I want to improve that by getting by sleep schedule in good pace.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Right now I’m redoing some stuff on the UI after some complaints. Things hopefully will look and feel better.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>April 1st Week - The Grind</title>
   <link href="/2022/04/04/April-w1/"/>
   <updated>2022-04-04T00:00:00+09:00</updated>
   <id>/website/2022/04/04/April-w1</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I fixed some small bugs and added some small features.  I tried to optimize the draw calls for the unity version but that was a can of worms. I don’t think I’ll do that for now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can try the game here: https://pidroh.github.io/GenericRPGIdle/&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is the time table for this week (week 13 of 2022):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;2022 W:13 hrpg       : 20:36:00
2022 W:13 manager    :  3:17:00
2022 W:13 marketing  :  0:42:00
2022 W:13 burocracy  :  0:29:00
2022 W:13 designer   :  0:30:00
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This week I will work tweaking the beginning of the game to make it more accessible. No big deal though. I also want to add keyboard support for popup messages. After that I’ll continue work on the feedback window. After that it’s either achievements or gamepad support.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gotta keep going [2]&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>March 4th Week - the Steam expansion continues (III)</title>
   <link href="/2022/03/28/March-w4/"/>
   <updated>2022-03-28T00:00:00+09:00</updated>
   <id>/website/2022/03/28/March-w4</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;A lot of progress was made in keyboard support. There must still be some small bugs though. I’ll probably need a moving cursor if I want to make keyboard input more obvious.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Right now I’m implementing a feedback form while also solving some small issues. The feedback form is requiring me to code a server for the game, which is a whole new experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can try the game here: https://pidroh.github.io/GenericRPGIdle/&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is the time table for this week (week 11 of 2022):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;2022 W:12 hrpg       : 20:56:00
2022 W:12 manager    :  3:14:00
2022 W:12 marketing  :  0:14:00
2022 W:12 designer   :  3:35:00
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This week wasn’t so productive. Had a fight with my SO which kinda threw me off balance emotionally :( things seem to be improving though.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was gonna be keyboard =&amp;gt; achievements =&amp;gt; gamepad, but now it’s
keyboard =&amp;gt; feedback form =&amp;gt; achievements =&amp;gt; gamepad&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gotta keep going.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>March 3rd Week - the Steam expansion continues (II)</title>
   <link href="/2022/03/21/March-w3/"/>
   <updated>2022-03-21T00:00:00+09:00</updated>
   <id>/website/2022/03/21/March-w3</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This week I added a way to automatically advance areas in the game. It takes a while to unlock, but it makes the game a lot more idle friendly. I’m now working on making the game being fully playable by using the keyboard. It was easier than I thought it would be, while at the same taking time because of unexpected bugs. It’s an ongoing progress.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can try the original version here: https://pidroh.github.io/GenericRPGIdle/
You can try the remake here: https://pidroh.github.io/GenericRPGIdle/unstable_phaser&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also got some points on the current palette of the game… A lot to fix.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is the time table for this week (week 11 of 2022):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;2022 W:11 hrpg       : 30:49:00
2022 W:11 manager    :  2:38:00
2022 W:11 marketing  :  1:00:00
2022 W:11 designer   :  0:25:00
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Keyboard will still take a while to get done. Maybe I’ll do keyboard =&amp;gt; achievements =&amp;gt; gamepad? 
I also need to worry about multiple screen resolution shenanigans…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gotta keep going.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>March 2nd Week - the Steam expansion continues</title>
   <link href="/2022/03/14/March-w2/"/>
   <updated>2022-03-14T00:00:00+09:00</updated>
   <id>/website/2022/03/14/March-w2</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The six first test achievements are in the game. They might changed or tweaked as the game progresses. I added local saves to the desktop version of the game. It was a HUGE mess. Had to change the library I use to create the jsons. It seems to be working. I have also managed to integrate the achievement system with Steam achievements, so that’s a win.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can try the original version here: https://pidroh.github.io/GenericRPGIdle/
You can try the remake here: https://pidroh.github.io/GenericRPGIdle/unstable_phaser&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I did some small UI tweaks too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is the time table for this week (week 10 of 2022):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;2022 W:10 hrpg       : 20:26:00
2022 W:10 manager    :  6:31:00
2022 W:10 marketing  :  0:29:00
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once again I mixed manager times with designer times. And I think I screwed up tracking hours on Friday. I think that is what happened anyways.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And off we go!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>March 1st Week - Remade... Kinda</title>
   <link href="/2022/03/07/March-w1/"/>
   <updated>2022-03-07T00:00:00+09:00</updated>
   <id>/website/2022/03/07/March-w1</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I have added tests and automation to the new version of the game. I have not brought over every feature from the original version yet. The new version has also has some new features, like correct piercing bonuses in Heavy Swords and Bastard Swords.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can try the original version here: https://pidroh.github.io/GenericRPGIdle/
You can try the remake here: https://pidroh.github.io/GenericRPGIdle/unstable_phaser&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last week was mainly fixed bugs. This week, though, I’m starting to implement achievements into the game. Just 6 simple achievements as a test though, for starters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is the time table for this week (week 9 of 2022):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;2022 W:09 manager    :  4:05:00
2022 W:09 marketing  :  0:40:00
2022 W:09 hrpg       :  31:32:00
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I guess I ended up mixing designer times with manager times? Anyways, good times this week. I actually had a small accident and broke a tooth lol. But it’s already fixed. Dentists are fast, I tell you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And off we go!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>February 4th Week - Slowly remaking (IV)</title>
   <link href="/2022/02/28/February-w4/"/>
   <updated>2022-02-28T00:00:00+09:00</updated>
   <id>/website/2022/02/28/February-w4</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I added a title screen to the remake version. I have also posted the remake version directly on Feedback Friday for the first time. Got me nervous there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can try the original version here: https://pidroh.github.io/GenericRPGIdle/
You can try the remake here: https://pidroh.github.io/GenericRPGIdle/unstable_phaser&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The remake has much better performance and will be the basis for the Steam version, so I will be focusing all development there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fixed some stuff on specific types of equipment. Got the remake running on Unity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is the time table for this week (week 8 of 2022):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;2022 W:08 hrpg       : 30:05:00
2022 W:08 manager    :  6:38:00
2022 W:08 marketing  :  1:17:00
2022 W:08 designer   :  1:08:00
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Got some nice performance this week since I stayed home for the weekend. That being said, I did find out that it is a submission process, which fails some people, for getting your game on Switch. I somehow thought it was super easy to get in. So being sucessful on Steam or another console would be a requirement. Life is complex hahaha. Not sure if I can realize my 2022 goal of publishing a game in consoles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And off we go!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>February 3nd Week - Slowly remaking (III)</title>
   <link href="/2022/02/21/February-w3/"/>
   <updated>2022-02-21T00:00:00+09:00</updated>
   <id>/website/2022/02/21/February-w3</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The region UI is now functional in the remake, but not complete yet. I fixed a lot of the problems with the equipment screen UI too.
I am now remaking the title screen UI!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can try the original version here: https://github.com/Pidroh/GenericRPGIdle&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is the time table for this week (week 7 of 2022):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;2022 W:07 hrpg       : 31:06:00
2022 W:07 manager    :  0:36:00
2022 W:07 marketing  :  0:17:00
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nice performance in general, but somehow I failed to track my designer hours, so it’s probably mixed with the game’s hours. I think.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And off we go!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>February 2nd Week - Slowly remaking (II)</title>
   <link href="/2022/02/14/February-w2/"/>
   <updated>2022-02-14T00:00:00+09:00</updated>
   <id>/website/2022/02/14/February-w2</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Not a lot of progress this week. Mainly worked on the in-battle area display. Also did a mockup for the new Region UI.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can try the original version here: https://github.com/Pidroh/GenericRPGIdle&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some pictures to illustrate how it is going:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Current Graphics&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/website/assets/original_2_14.png&quot; alt=&quot;My helpful screenshot&quot; /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Mockup (the goal)&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/website/assets/mockup_2_14.png&quot; alt=&quot;My helpful screenshot&quot; /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;In progress&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/website/assets/remake_2_14.png&quot; alt=&quot;My helpful screenshot&quot; /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;__&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;__&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;__&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;__&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;__&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;__&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;__&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;__&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;__&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;__&lt;/strong&gt;_
&lt;strong&gt;__&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;__&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;__&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;__&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;__&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;__&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;__&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;__&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;__&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;__&lt;/strong&gt;_&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is the time table for this week (week 4 of 2022):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;2022 W:06 manager    :  0:12:00
2022 W:06 marketing  :  2:04:00
2022 W:06 hrpg       : 21:51:00
2022 W:06 designer   :  0:34:00
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This week Friday was a holiday, so that was nice. But I went on a trip for the weekend, which ate up a bunch of hours. This week I hope to be able to get the region / area tab functional. Then I’ll need to fix up the problems in the equipment UI. After that work on buff visualization and set selection.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And off we go!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>February 1st Week - Slowly remaking</title>
   <link href="/2022/02/07/February-w1/"/>
   <updated>2022-02-07T00:00:00+09:00</updated>
   <id>/website/2022/02/07/February-w1</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Made some great progress on the equipment screen. I also implemented some requests from players to the on-air version.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can try the original version here: https://github.com/Pidroh/GenericRPGIdle&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is the time table for this week (week 4 of 2022):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;2022 W:05 hrpg       :  28:31:00
2022 W:05 marketing  :  3:00:00
2022 W:05 manager    :  2:15:00
2022 W:05 designer   :  0:00:00
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;37 hours in on GRI again! Once again, good numbers!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So my path has been:
Haxe UI =&amp;gt; Pure KHA =&amp;gt; Haxe JS Canvas =&amp;gt; Haxe Phaser.js&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And I think I’ll stick with Phaser, it seems to be reliable. Steam will probably use Electron. If I port to consoles, then I guess I’ll port to Unity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;February is here! And also, happy Chinese new year to those who celebrate it!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>January 5th Week - Remaking!</title>
   <link href="/2022/01/31/january-w5/"/>
   <updated>2022-01-31T00:00:00+09:00</updated>
   <id>/website/2022/01/31/january-w5</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;My new custom made renderer and UI system is starting to get pretty stable, so I’ll keep building the game. Next week I’ll see if I can get a playable build to gather some feedback.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is the time table for this week (week 4 of 2022):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;2022 W:04 hrpg       :  37:01:00
2022 W:04 marketing  :  0:25:00
2022 W:04 manager    :  0:32:00
2022 W:04 designer   :  1:52:00
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;37 hours in on GRI again! Once again, good numbers!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So my path has been:
Haxe UI =&amp;gt; Pure KHA =&amp;gt; Haxe JS Canvas =&amp;gt; Haxe Phaser.js&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And I think I’ll stick with Phaser, it seems to be reliable. Steam will probably use Electron. If I port to consoles, then I guess I’ll port to Unity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;February is here! And also, happy Chinese new year to those who celebrate it!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>January 4th Week - R&D Week!</title>
   <link href="/2022/01/24/january-w4/"/>
   <updated>2022-01-24T00:00:00+09:00</updated>
   <id>/website/2022/01/24/january-w4</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;So last week we pushed a big update on Steam. This week, though… I have recently discovered that using Haxe UI for a console release would be a bit shaky. So I decided to:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A) Create my own highly portable UI system
B) port generic RPG to that&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And things have been messy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is the time table for this week (week 3 of 2022):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;2022 W:03 hrpg       :  37:21:00
2022 W:03 housework  :  0:59:00
2022 W:03 marketing  :  3:52:00
2022 W:03 manager    :  5:28:00
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I got 37 hours in on GRI. It’s pretty easy to get a lot of hours in when you’re trying to implement a basic rendering engine and I keep moving between libraries. My concentration goes up the roof lol. Currently, I went from:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Haxe UI =&amp;gt; Pure KHA =&amp;gt; Haxe JS Canvas =&amp;gt; Haxe Phaser.js&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Haxe Phaser.js does seem to be the best option for targetting browsers, so I guess I’ll keep going with that. Hope I don’t hit any roadblocks :(&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>January 3rd Week - New Update & Steam Page is up!</title>
   <link href="/2022/01/17/january-w3/"/>
   <updated>2022-01-17T00:00:00+09:00</updated>
   <id>/website/2022/01/17/january-w3</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Big update on the UI and the Steam page is up!!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can try the game here: https://pidroh.github.io/GenericRPGIdle/&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A lot of hover information, turn-order visualization, and other goodies came with the new UI.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is the time table for this week (week 2 of 2022):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;2022 W:02 hrpg       :  25:26:00
2022 W:02 manager    :  2:39:00
2022 W:02 marketing  :  1:07:00
2022 W:02 designer   :  6:04:00
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Got 25 hours in generic rpg idle. A lot less than last week. This weekend I was pretty busy so I guess that is the reason. I was planning to port GRI to consoles, but that idea went north as I found out that the Haxe UI ecosystem isn’t that robust. Trying to figure out what I want to aim for in this year. Having trouble.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ll see how it goes!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>January 2nd Week - Next version still in development!</title>
   <link href="/2022/01/10/january-w2/"/>
   <updated>2022-01-10T00:00:00+09:00</updated>
   <id>/website/2022/01/10/january-w2</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Things are the same as last week! Still working hard on the new update for the game that will change the UI and the looks of the game big time. 
While I’m getting that ready, there aren’t any updates in the game for now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can try the game here: https://pidroh.github.io/GenericRPGIdle/&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is the time table for this week (week 1 of 2022):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;2022 W:01 hrpg       :  34:32:00
2022 W:01 manager    :  2:37:00
2022 W:01 marketing  :  0:31:00
2022 W:01 designer   :  0:20:00

&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Got 34 hours in. I’m almost done with the new version. Should be coming next week. Where I live is getting pretty cold, hope everyone is safe during these times.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>January 1st Week: HAPPY NEW YEAR!</title>
   <link href="/2022/01/05/january-w1/"/>
   <updated>2022-01-05T00:00:00+09:00</updated>
   <id>/website/2022/01/05/january-w1</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I’m working hard on a new update for the game that will change the UI and the looks of the game big time. 
While I’m getting that ready, there aren’t any updates in the game for now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can try the game here: https://pidroh.github.io/GenericRPGIdle/&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is the time table for this week (week 1 of 2022):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;2021 W:52 hrpg       : 20:19:00
2021 W:52 marketing  :  2:14:00
2022 W:52 hrpg       :  5:18:00
2022 W:52 manager    :  0:50:00
2022 W:52 designer   :  4:34:00

&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s a bit confusing but I guess I got 25 hours in of working on Generic RPG Idle. Not bad.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I plan to finish the artwork rework soon. The problem is that it will come with a bunch of broken stuff that will need fixing. Maybe the next build will only come in two weeks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;HAPPY NEW YEAR!!!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>December 4th Week: Merry Christmas!!</title>
   <link href="/2021/12/28/december-w4/"/>
   <updated>2021-12-28T00:00:00+09:00</updated>
   <id>/website/2021/12/28/december-w4</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Elemental skills and equipment sets implemented in the game!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can try the game here: https://pidroh.github.io/GenericRPGIdle/&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is the time table for this week (week 51 of 2021):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;2021 W:51 auto       :  9:04:00
2021 W:51 manager    :  0:28:00
2021 W:51 hrpg       : 21:44:00
2021 W:51 designer   :  4:44:00
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I spent a lot of time working on a new build system to handle the multiple versions of the game. It’s in multiple sites now. I have also spent way too much time thinking about the graphics of the game. I’ll have to rethink everything going forward with the game when I add more cutscenes to the game.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>December 3rd Week: Released on Itch IO and I am out of the hospital!</title>
   <link href="/2021/12/20/december-w3/"/>
   <updated>2021-12-20T00:00:00+09:00</updated>
   <id>/website/2021/12/20/december-w3</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Upgrading equipment and the dark theme is in the Itch IO version! I’ll upload the github version later. 
I have developed a system for magical skills and elemental damage. I am working on revising the UI.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can try the Itch IO version here: https://pidroh.itch.io/generic-rpg-idle&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is the time table for this week (week 50 of 2021):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;2021 W:50 hrpg       : 30:51:00
2021 W:50 marketing  :  1:04:00
2021 W:50 manager    :  3:48:00
2021 W:50 designer   :  3:55:00
2021 W:50 auto       :  0:08:00
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;30 hours done on programming, mainly because I was in the hospital. Maybe I got a bit more work since I screwed up the tracking with all the little things in the hospital. Not sure. The surgery went great so all is well! My nose is still getting clogged up but things are great.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ll add some UI mockups at a later date! Let’s go HRPG!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>December 2nd Week: Taking a bit more time to release the new version</title>
   <link href="/2021/12/13/december-w2/"/>
   <updated>2021-12-13T00:00:00+09:00</updated>
   <id>/website/2021/12/13/december-w2</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;IN DEVELOPMENT: The ability to upgrade equipment. A new dark color scheme of the UI.
I might add an option for going back to the old color scheme if there is a wish for it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While the game hasn’t changed from last week, you can try it here: https://github.com/Pidroh/GenericRPGIdle&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is the time table for this week (week 49 of 2021):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;2021 W:49 hrpg       : 1 day, 1:09:00
2021 W:49 marketing  :  3:41:00
2021 W:49 burocracy  :  0:59:00
2021 W:49 designer   :  1:25:00
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;25 hours programming, not so bad. A little bit less work done this week. I was kinda busy in the weekend.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I ended up delaying elemental spells to focus on upgrading equipment. So the last battle system expansion will be the elemental spells. That will likely come with an overhaul of Lagrima Continent, maybe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m typing this from the hospital. My surgery is tomorrow. The hospital is pretty confortable so I guess I can get a lot of work done!&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>December 1st Week: Polish+ and Rebalance!</title>
   <link href="/2021/12/06/december-w1/"/>
   <updated>2021-12-06T00:00:00+09:00</updated>
   <id>/website/2021/12/06/december-w1</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The game’s interface should look better and progress in the game should be faster. I have also tweaked a bunch of other things and added more bosses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can try it here: https://github.com/Pidroh/GenericRPGIdle&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is the time table for this week (week 48 of 2021):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;2021 W:48 hrpg       : 22:37:00
2021 W:48 manager    :  3:29:00
2021 W:48 designer   : 16:46:00
2021 W:48 marketing  :  1:10:00
2021 W:48 burocracy  :  1:49:00
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;22 hours programming, a bit down. The reason is the 16 hours of ‘designer’. I guess I was thinking about various aspects of the game? I don’t remember hahaha&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will now tackle elemental spells! Or maybe something else since elemental spells will require me to overhaul some parts of enemy generation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next week I’ll do a small surgery so I’ll work on the game more? Or maybe less? Who knows!&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>November 4th Week: Generic RPG Idle Skill Sets and Magic Points</title>
   <link href="/2021/11/29/november-w4/"/>
   <updated>2021-11-29T00:00:00+09:00</updated>
   <id>/website/2021/11/29/november-w4</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This was a big change towards making the game more active (not sure on how well it worked though lol).
Now you have multiple sets of skill to choose from and you have to manually use skills during battle. You can defeat some bosses faster and stuff.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;BE WARNED&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;THE PROTOTYPE IS VERY SIMPLE AND BORING. YOU KINDA JUST LEAVE IT RUNNING IN THE BROWSE, CHOOSE YOUR EQUIPMENT AND WHERE TO FIGHT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can try it here: https://github.com/Pidroh/GenericRPGIdle&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is the time table for this week (week 47 of 2021):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;2021-11 W:47 hrpg       :  1 day, 13:06:00
2021-11 W:47 marketing  :  0:18:00
2021-11 W:47 designer   :  3:15:00
2021-11 W:47 burocracy  :  0:38:00
2021-11 W:47 manager    :  6:04:00
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;37 hours programming, it was productive too compared to last week. The 6 hours in manager and designer are trying to decide on how to handle the post game and how to add money to the game.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>November 3rd Week: Generic RPG Idle item system revamp</title>
   <link href="/2021/11/22/november-w3/"/>
   <updated>2021-11-22T00:00:00+09:00</updated>
   <id>/website/2021/11/22/november-w3</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I have changed how the item system works. Items now have names, different types, and different rarities. This allows for a higher range of play styles than before.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;BE WARNED&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;THE PROTOTYPE IS VERY SIMPLE AND BORING. YOU KINDA JUST LEAVE IT RUNNING IN THE BROWSE, CHOOSE YOUR EQUIPMENT AND WHERE TO FIGHT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can try it here: https://github.com/Pidroh/GenericRPGIdle&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is the time table for this week (week 46 of 2021):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;2021-11 W:46 manager    :  2:39:00
2021-11 W:46 hrpg       : 1 day, 12:53:00
2021-11 W:46 marketing  :  2:46:00
2021-11 W:46 burocracy  :  0:14:00
2021-11 W:46 designer   :  2:27:00
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lots of programming but a lot of it wasn’t so productive. I feel like I spent a lot of time rethinking things, having analysis paralysis and just play testing too much. But still, 36 hours making the game is nice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next update will take a while and will feature magic. It will change how the game is played quite a bit.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>November 2st Week: Generic RPG Idle battle system entering the last phase</title>
   <link href="/2021/11/15/november-w2/"/>
   <updated>2021-11-15T00:00:00+09:00</updated>
   <id>/website/2021/11/15/november-w2</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I have added a prestige system to Generic RPG to make the game a bit more dynamic. It plays well with the newly added bosses, I think.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;BE WARNED&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;THE PROTOTYPE IS VERY SIMPLE AND BORING. YOU KINDA JUST LEAVE IT RUNNING IN THE BROWSE, CHOOSE YOUR EQUIPMENT AND WHERE TO FIGHT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can try it here: https://github.com/Pidroh/GenericRPGIdle&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have finished the full specification for the RPG systems in Brave Ball! With this in hand, I now have the long road ahead of implementing all of those systems in Generic RPG Idle. I have also decided to do the map system in Haxe. A lot of development will be happening there, I want to develop it in an easier to prototype environment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is the time table for this week (week 45 of 2021):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;2021-11 W:45 hrpg       : 23:21:00
2021-11 W:45 manager    :  0:25:00
2021-11 W:45 marketing  :  4:56:00
2021-11 W:45 burocracy  :  2:46:00
2021-11 W:45 designer   : 11:23:00
2021-11 W:45 auto       :  0:24:00
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Less programming. 11 hours of me thinking and writing down the systems for Brave Ball! 23 hours for Generic RPG, not bad.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s go!!!!!!!!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>November 1st Week: Back to Brave Ball a bit</title>
   <link href="/2021/11/09/november-w1/"/>
   <updated>2021-11-09T00:00:00+09:00</updated>
   <id>/website/2021/11/09/november-w1</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Added new bosses to the prototype!!! They give permanent stat upgrades. I did add further cutscenes to the game, but stopped myself from adding goals. The reason for that is because adding goals would make for a better game, I might not use it in Brave Ball. I might reconsider adding a similar system to Brave Ball though.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;BE WARNED&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;THE PROTOTYPE IS VERY SIMPLE AND BORING. YOU KINDA JUST LEAVE IT RUNNING IN THE BROWSE, CHOOSE YOUR EQUIPMENT AND WHERE TO FIGHT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can try it here: https://github.com/Pidroh/GenericRPGIdle&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also wrote all the cutscenes that will be in the Brave Ball demo! It was super fun.
Now I need to write code to integrate the cutscenes with the map. Not sure if I should write new map code in Haxe and do the integration in Haxe… Or move over to C# and do it there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is the time table for this week (week 44 of 2021):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;2021-11 W:44 hrpg       : 26:33:00
2021-11 W:44 marketing  :  3:47:00
2021-11 W:44 manager    :  3:20:00
2021-11 W:44 auto       :  0:30:00
2021-11 W:44 turn       : 12:28:00
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;26 hours programming the prototype and 12 hours planning and writing cutscenes for Brave Ball! Not bad!
Right now I’m adding a prestige system to HRPG, which might make it into Brave Ball. This Saturday I’ll make a decision on where to integrate the cutscenes to the map.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s go!!!!!!!!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>October 4th Week: Keeps going</title>
   <link href="/2021/11/01/october-w4-Copy/"/>
   <updated>2021-11-01T00:00:00+09:00</updated>
   <id>/website/2021/11/01/october-w4 - Copy</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Normal week hahaha I added armors and more stats to my prototype.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;BE WARNED&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;THE PROTOTYPE IS VERY SIMPLE AND BORING. YOU KINDA JUST LEAVE IT RUNNING IN THE BROWSE AND YOU CAN ONLY CHOOSE WHICH AREA TO FIGHT IN&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can try it here: https://github.com/Pidroh/GenericRPGIdle&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some users found bugs that I have no idea how to fix :( sad&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is the time table for this week (week 43 of 2021):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;2021-10 W:43 design     :  0:11:00
2021-10 W:43 hrpg       : 22:55:00
2021-10 W:43 manager    :  0:55:00
2021-10 W:43 marketing  :  6:09:00
2021-10 W:43 auto       :  0:27:00
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My times are back to normal hahahaha no more 30 hour programming in a week. Makes sense! I had to stop by the hospital too, which is a huge time drain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While I have some cutscenes in the game, I’m expanding on that. Also having more clearly defined, visible goals in the game.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>October 3nd Week: No stops!</title>
   <link href="/2021/10/26/october-w3/"/>
   <updated>2021-10-26T00:00:00+09:00</updated>
   <id>/website/2021/10/26/october-w3</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;A very normal week hahaha. I added swords to my simple prototype.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;BE WARNED&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;THE PROTOTYPE IS VERY SIMPLE AND BORING. YOU KINDA JUST LEAVE IT RUNNING IN THE BROWSE AND YOU CAN ONLY CHOOSE WHICH AREA TO FIGHT IN&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can try it here: https://github.com/Pidroh/GenericRPGIdle&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is the time table for this week (week 42 of 2021):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;2021-10 W:42 manager    :  1:50:00
2021-10 W:42 marketing  :  5:08:00
2021-10 W:42 hrpg       : 1 day, 6:47:00
2021-10 W:42 designer   :  6:57:00
2021-10 W:42 auto       :  0:50:00
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This week I got way more work in. This post, though, was supposed to be posted yesterday, so that is bad.
Marketing and designer time went up. I was kinda lost during that designer time, so I’m not sure if it was quality time being spent, but maybe it was necessary.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have stopped a bit on the RPG mechanics and started to create the code for the story. Hopefully I can get story cutscenes working before Friday but that may be tough.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>October 2nd Week: Development is going!</title>
   <link href="/2021/10/18/october-w2/"/>
   <updated>2021-10-18T00:00:00+09:00</updated>
   <id>/website/2021/10/18/october-w2</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;So I guess the main news today is the first trial of the Level Up and XP system for Brave Ball. I am not sure if I want to go with fixed XP per level and weak enemies giving less XP, or if I just go with higher and higher XP flowing in. Right now I’ll just leave the higher and higher XP values.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;BE WARNED&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;THE PROTOTYPE IS VERY SIMPLE AND BORING. YOU KINDA JUST LEAVE IT RUNNING IN THE BROWSE AND YOU CAN ONLY CHOOSE WHICH AREA TO FIGHT IN&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can try it here: https://github.com/Pidroh/GenericRPGIdle&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, the initial balance is bad! You’re gonna have a hard time before you get your first level up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is the time table for this week (week 41 of 2021):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;2021-10 W:41 manager    :  1:28:00
2021-10 W:41 hrpg       : 21:29:00
2021-10 W:41 marketing  :  0:53:00
2021-10 W:41 auto       :  0:00:00
2021-10 W:41 designer   :  3:36:00
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This week I got little work in. I was a bit busy in the weekend and I have been feeling a bit sick (some bad nutritional choices I plan to fix this week, way too much powdered food, fiber and caffeine dehydrating me). Next weekend I’ll be less busy so I think I can bring those numbers up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Marketing is now down to one hour. This has a reason though, this is because I decided to move some marketing activities to Monday (which resulted in almost no big marketing for that week, kinda of delaying some posts).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This week the haxe prototype continues BUT I am also writing a bit the story of Brave Ball. By knowing exactly where I want the demo to end, I can start think about how I am going to order the art I need for the game. With this, I can draw a budget for the game. I hope.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Steam Fest ended :(</title>
   <link href="/2021/10/11/october-w1/"/>
   <updated>2021-10-11T00:00:00+09:00</updated>
   <id>/website/2021/10/11/october-w1</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Brave Ball went strong on Steam Fest!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/website/assets/steamfest.png&quot; alt=&quot;Brave Ball on Steam Fest screenshot&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m currently prototyping the RPG mechanics as a browser game!
And soon &lt;strong&gt;everyone&lt;/strong&gt; will be able to play the prototype! That means you, reader!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Currently the balance is super bad though. And it’s an idle game, so, not sure if everyone will like it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ll post a link here in October 18th!!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is the time table for this week (week 40 of 2021):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;2021-10 W:40 marketing  :  3:04:00
2021-10 W:40 housework  :  0:16:00
2021-10 W:40 manager    :  2:04:00
2021-10 W:40 hrpg       : 17:29:00
2021-10 W:40            :  0:01:00
2021-10 W:40 auto       :  5:24:00

&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Around 23 hours of programming in!!! Nice!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Marketing is now down to 3 hours. This makes sense because I didn’t really have any new screenshots to show or pages to seetup.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This week is mainly the haxe prototype but I am kinda stuck in knowing how much I should balance VS adding new features. Hard to make a prototype fun when it doesn’t have enough features.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>We are on Steam Fest!!!</title>
   <link href="/2021/10/04/september-w4/"/>
   <updated>2021-10-04T00:00:00+09:00</updated>
   <id>/website/2021/10/04/september-w4</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Brave Ball is on Steam Fest so I hope more people are playing the demo!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/website/assets/steamfest.png&quot; alt=&quot;My helpful screenshot&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also got a lot of feedback from people so it’s a good chance to improve the game.
There are some input bugs that I need to fix and I’m fixing about changing the input system backend. Unity is really troublesome!!!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is the time table for this week (week 39 of 2021):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;2021-09 W:39 turn       :  4:04:00
2021-09 W:39 hrpg       :  7:49:00
2021-09 W:39 marketing  :  4:22:00
2021-10 W:39 hrpg       :  8:53:00
2021-10 W:39 turn       :  4:56:00
2021-10 W:39 marketing  :  2:00:00
2021-10 W:39 manager    :  2:30:00
2021-10 W:39 designer   :  1:29:00
2021-10 W:39 automation :  3:02:00
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately week 39 is split between September and October. 24 hours of programming in!!! Nice!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Marketing is like six hours, not sure on how I feel about that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Programming is split between turn, which is basically Unity stuff. hrpg is mainly me prototyping the RPG mechanisms of the game in Haxe. I wanna write about that more later.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Project Planning for a single developer</title>
   <link href="/2021/09/26/project-planning/"/>
   <updated>2021-09-26T00:00:00+09:00</updated>
   <id>/website/2021/09/26/project-planning</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h1 id=&quot;problem&quot;&gt;Problem&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am trying to find a better way to structure the way I work as a single developer. 
I find that I have a lot of “stuck thinking” time because I wear many hats at the same time. When I should be doing programming, I’ll sometimes be stuck thinking about game design or about the graphics. Or I’ll be stuck thinking “should I be doing something else?!”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The good thing about working as a team is that people decide as a team and then you go do your work. If you think you should be working on something else, then you need to wait to talk about that in the next meeting. But if you’re a single developer you can be very agile and change what you are doing freely. This creates a lot of flexibility but it also makes a lot of things bad.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;bad-performance-because-of-context-switching&quot;&gt;Bad performance because of context-switching&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;thinking about project management or game design while I should be programming&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;wandering-in-the-desert&quot;&gt;Wandering in the desert&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Allowing me to change what I am doing in the heat of the moment or get stuck thinking about it makes it more likely I am not working towards the “vision of the project”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;hard-to-commit&quot;&gt;Hard to commit&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will sometimes schedule time for marketing but then make a decision that “I don’t need to do marketing lately because of X”, then go on to program.
I think that by delaying that decision to later, I can make a more informed decision.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;solution&quot;&gt;Solution&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;weekly-public-management-blog&quot;&gt;Weekly public management blog&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Write weekly about how the week went and post times for each profession.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;schedule-time-for-each-profession&quot;&gt;Schedule time for each profession&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every profession should try to do only their minimal time, while the programmer can work as much as they want.
If there is not enough time to do the work, they should write a note for the team meeting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;game-designer&quot;&gt;Game Designer&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Decides what will be put in the game&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Play tests, brainstorms, rebalances&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;programmer&quot;&gt;Programmer&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Programs functionality decided by the game designer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;automation-programmer&quot;&gt;Automation Programmer&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Programs functionality decided by the manager&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;marketer&quot;&gt;Marketer&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Writes blog posts&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Takes screenshots, gifs and videos&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Uploads builds&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;manager---team-meeting&quot;&gt;Manager - Team Meeting&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Checks if every job is doing their weekly time&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Rethinks how time should be spent in the project&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Decides what the automation programmer should make&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Assigns tasks to everyone&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Write the weekly write up&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Rethinks this whole team planning thing and considers if reverting to the flexible style is better&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;producer&quot;&gt;Producer&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Checks if the game is going according to vision&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let us see how well this works hahahaha good luck, me.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Working hard to improve Brave Ball's graphics</title>
   <link href="/2021/09/25/new-graphics-for-brave-ball/"/>
   <updated>2021-09-25T00:00:00+09:00</updated>
   <id>/website/2021/09/25/new-graphics-for-brave-ball</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Tell us what you think of the new art direction for the scenario!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pedro from Pidroh Games here! Hope everyone is doing fine!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lately I have decided to improve the art direction for the scenario and made some experiments.
You can see the 3 current ideas for areas we have in the gif below.
&lt;img src=&quot;/website/assets/gameplay_scenariochange.gif&quot; alt=&quot;My helpful screenshot&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We think the new balance of light, darkness and contrast makes the game easier to play.
&lt;img src=&quot;/website/assets/SavedScreen202109240825214403.png&quot; alt=&quot;My helpful screenshot&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/website/assets/gameplayt.gif&quot; alt=&quot;My helpful screenshot&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/website/assets/lightmockupb.png&quot; alt=&quot;My helpful screenshot&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/website/assets/SavedScreen202109240828267823.png&quot; alt=&quot;My helpful screenshot&quot; /&gt;
Do let us know if you have any thoughts on the direction we are going!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 

</feed>
