<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

 <title>Pidroh</title>
 <link href="/website/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
 <link href="/website/"/>
 <updated>2021-10-26T08:21:45+09:00</updated>
 <id></id>
 <author>
   <name>Pedro Gabriel Fonteles Furtado</name>
   <email>gabrielpff2@gmail.com</email>
 </author>

 
 <entry>
   <title>October 2nd Week: Development is going!</title>
   <link href="/2021/10/26/october-w3/"/>
   <updated>2021-10-26T00:00:00+09:00</updated>
   <id>/website/2021/10/26/october-w3</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;A very normal week hahaha. I added swords to my simple prototype.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;BE WARNED&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;THE PROTOTYPE IS VERY SIMPLE AND BORING. YOU KINDA JUST LEAVE IT RUNNING IN THE BROWSE AND YOU CAN ONLY CHOOSE WHICH AREA TO FIGHT IN&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can try it here: https://github.com/Pidroh/GenericRPGIdle&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is the time table for this week (week 41 of 2021):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;2021-10 W:42 manager    :  1:50:00
2021-10 W:42 marketing  :  5:08:00
2021-10 W:42 hrpg       : 1 day, 6:47:00
2021-10 W:42 designer   :  6:57:00
2021-10 W:42 auto       :  0:50:00
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This week I got way more work in. This post, though, was supposed to be posted yesterday, so that is bad.
Marketing and designer time went up. I was kinda lost during that designer time, so I’m not sure if it was quality time being spent, but maybe it was necessary.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have stopped a bit on the RPG mechanics and started to create the code for the story.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>October 2nd Week: Development is going!</title>
   <link href="/2021/10/18/october-w2/"/>
   <updated>2021-10-18T00:00:00+09:00</updated>
   <id>/website/2021/10/18/october-w2</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;So I guess the main news today is the first trial of the Level Up and XP system for Brave Ball. I am not sure if I want to go with fixed XP per level and weak enemies giving less XP, or if I just go with higher and higher XP flowing in. Right now I’ll just leave the higher and higher XP values.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;BE WARNED&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;THE PROTOTYPE IS VERY SIMPLE AND BORING. YOU KINDA JUST LEAVE IT RUNNING IN THE BROWSE AND YOU CAN ONLY CHOOSE WHICH AREA TO FIGHT IN&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can try it here: https://github.com/Pidroh/GenericRPGIdle&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, the initial balance is bad! You’re gonna have a hard time before you get your first level up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is the time table for this week (week 41 of 2021):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;2021-10 W:41 manager    :  1:28:00
2021-10 W:41 hrpg       : 21:29:00
2021-10 W:41 marketing  :  0:53:00
2021-10 W:41 auto       :  0:00:00
2021-10 W:41 designer   :  3:36:00
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This week I got little work in. I was a bit busy in the weekend and I have been feeling a bit sick (some bad nutritional choices I plan to fix this week, way too much powdered food, fiber and caffeine dehydrating me). Next weekend I’ll be less busy so I think I can bring those numbers up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Marketing is now down to one hour. This has a reason though, this is because I decided to move some marketing activities to Monday (which resulted in almost no big marketing for that week, kinda of delaying some posts).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This week the haxe prototype continues BUT I am also writing a bit the story of Brave Ball. By knowing exactly where I want the demo to end, I can start think about how I am going to order the art I need for the game. With this, I can draw a budget for the game. I hope.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Steam Fest ended :(</title>
   <link href="/2021/10/11/october-w1/"/>
   <updated>2021-10-11T00:00:00+09:00</updated>
   <id>/website/2021/10/11/october-w1</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Brave Ball went strong on Steam Fest!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/website/assets/steamfest.png&quot; alt=&quot;Brave Ball on Steam Fest screenshot&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m currently prototyping the RPG mechanics as a browser game!
And soon &lt;strong&gt;everyone&lt;/strong&gt; will be able to play the prototype! That means you, reader!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Currently the balance is super bad though. And it’s an idle game, so, not sure if everyone will like it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ll post a link here in October 18th!!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is the time table for this week (week 40 of 2021):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;2021-10 W:40 marketing  :  3:04:00
2021-10 W:40 housework  :  0:16:00
2021-10 W:40 manager    :  2:04:00
2021-10 W:40 hrpg       : 17:29:00
2021-10 W:40            :  0:01:00
2021-10 W:40 auto       :  5:24:00

&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Around 23 hours of programming in!!! Nice!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Marketing is now down to 3 hours. This makes sense because I didn’t really have any new screenshots to show or pages to seetup.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This week is mainly the haxe prototype but I am kinda stuck in knowing how much I should balance VS adding new features. Hard to make a prototype fun when it doesn’t have enough features.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>We are on Steam Fest!!!</title>
   <link href="/2021/10/04/september-w4/"/>
   <updated>2021-10-04T00:00:00+09:00</updated>
   <id>/website/2021/10/04/september-w4</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Brave Ball is on Steam Fest so I hope more people are playing the demo!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/website/assets/steamfest.png&quot; alt=&quot;My helpful screenshot&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also got a lot of feedback from people so it’s a good chance to improve the game.
There are some input bugs that I need to fix and I’m fixing about changing the input system backend. Unity is really troublesome!!!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is the time table for this week (week 39 of 2021):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;2021-09 W:39 turn       :  4:04:00
2021-09 W:39 hrpg       :  7:49:00
2021-09 W:39 marketing  :  4:22:00
2021-10 W:39 hrpg       :  8:53:00
2021-10 W:39 turn       :  4:56:00
2021-10 W:39 marketing  :  2:00:00
2021-10 W:39 manager    :  2:30:00
2021-10 W:39 designer   :  1:29:00
2021-10 W:39 automation :  3:02:00
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately week 39 is split between September and October. 24 hours of programming in!!! Nice!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Marketing is like six hours, not sure on how I feel about that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Programming is split between turn, which is basically Unity stuff. hrpg is mainly me prototyping the RPG mechanisms of the game in Haxe. I wanna write about that more later.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Project Planning for a single developer</title>
   <link href="/2021/09/26/project-planning/"/>
   <updated>2021-09-26T00:00:00+09:00</updated>
   <id>/website/2021/09/26/project-planning</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h1 id=&quot;problem&quot;&gt;Problem&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am trying to find a better way to structure the way I work as a single developer. 
I find that I have a lot of “stuck thinking” time because I wear many hats at the same time. When I should be doing programming, I’ll sometimes be stuck thinking about game design or about the graphics. Or I’ll be stuck thinking “should I be doing something else?!”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The good thing about working as a team is that people decide as a team and then you go do your work. If you think you should be working on something else, then you need to wait to talk about that in the next meeting. But if you’re a single developer you can be very agile and change what you are doing freely. This creates a lot of flexibility but it also makes a lot of things bad.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;bad-performance-because-of-context-switching&quot;&gt;Bad performance because of context-switching&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;thinking about project management or game design while I should be programming&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;wandering-in-the-desert&quot;&gt;Wandering in the desert&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Allowing me to change what I am doing in the heat of the moment or get stuck thinking about it makes it more likely I am not working towards the “vision of the project”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;hard-to-commit&quot;&gt;Hard to commit&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will sometimes schedule time for marketing but then make a decision that “I don’t need to do marketing lately because of X”, then go on to program.
I think that by delaying that decision to later, I can make a more informed decision.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;solution&quot;&gt;Solution&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;weekly-public-management-blog&quot;&gt;Weekly public management blog&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Write weekly about how the week went and post times for each profession.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;schedule-time-for-each-profession&quot;&gt;Schedule time for each profession&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every profession should try to do only their minimal time, while the programmer can work as much as they want.
If there is not enough time to do the work, they should write a note for the team meeting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;game-designer&quot;&gt;Game Designer&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Decides what will be put in the game&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Play tests, brainstorms, rebalances&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;programmer&quot;&gt;Programmer&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Programs functionality decided by the game designer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;automation-programmer&quot;&gt;Automation Programmer&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Programs functionality decided by the manager&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;marketer&quot;&gt;Marketer&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Writes blog posts&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Takes screenshots, gifs and videos&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Uploads builds&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;manager---team-meeting&quot;&gt;Manager - Team Meeting&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Checks if every job is doing their weekly time&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Rethinks how time should be spent in the project&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Decides what the automation programmer should make&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Assigns tasks to everyone&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Write the weekly write up&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Rethinks this whole team planning thing and considers if reverting to the flexible style is better&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;producer&quot;&gt;Producer&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Checks if the game is going according to vision&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let us see how well this works hahahaha good luck, me.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Working hard to improve Brave Ball's graphics</title>
   <link href="/2021/09/25/new-graphics-for-brave-ball/"/>
   <updated>2021-09-25T00:00:00+09:00</updated>
   <id>/website/2021/09/25/new-graphics-for-brave-ball</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Tell us what you think of the new art direction for the scenario!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pedro from Pidroh Games here! Hope everyone is doing fine!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lately I have decided to improve the art direction for the scenario and made some experiments.
You can see the 3 current ideas for areas we have in the gif below.
&lt;img src=&quot;/website/assets/gameplay_scenariochange.gif&quot; alt=&quot;My helpful screenshot&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We think the new balance of light, darkness and contrast makes the game easier to play.
&lt;img src=&quot;/website/assets/SavedScreen202109240825214403.png&quot; alt=&quot;My helpful screenshot&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/website/assets/gameplayt.gif&quot; alt=&quot;My helpful screenshot&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/website/assets/lightmockupb.png&quot; alt=&quot;My helpful screenshot&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/website/assets/SavedScreen202109240828267823.png&quot; alt=&quot;My helpful screenshot&quot; /&gt;
Do let us know if you have any thoughts on the direction we are going!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 

</feed>
